Okay, we're back in VS Code. Now we're going to go through and build some more resources.
And build further on our infrastructure, because now we have our resource group, we have our VNet, we have our subnet.
So now we're going to build a security, network security group, which will be added onto the subnet.
Because we want to build a virtual machine afterwards, and then we want to use the security group to block or only allow, for example, my private or my public IP address.
This is the only one that is allowed to connect to the machine, because if you install an Azure thing that is open to the whole world, it doesn't take long before you notice that this is open for RDP, or this is open for SSH.
And then there will be many who will try to log on to this with brute force, and if you have a weak password, then this will be cracked pretty quickly.
And then the machine can become part of a distributed denial of service botnet, which we absolutely do not want.
Not that it's a topic for the rest of us, since we tear this infrastructure quickly after each time we're done, but it's at least a security measure you should take and be aware of that you have to go through and do to ensure that your infrastructure is secure.
But this is just a test project, we're going through some infrastructure with Terraform, so we'll do it that way.
We only allow my official IP address, which is allowed to enter there. You have to find out your official address by going to whatismyipaddress.com, and then find the one you want to enter, but we'll come to that and show it.
We start by going to documentation, we go to registry.terraform.io, as we did last time. Here we choose Browse Providers, choose Azure, go to documentation, and then we can search here Network Security Group.
Then we see here Resources, Security Group, Security Rule, and Security Group Association, because we have to add it onto the subnet.
We start with the Security Group, and then we see here under our example, right here we have the Resource Group, and here we have a resource that is for Network Security Group.
We could of course write it, but if we take it with us now into VS Code, then we can see how we can simply just copy the information in from the documentation.
We remember as before, Resources, Azure, RM Network Security Group, it's another name for the resource, we can't change it.
Here we can write, for example, NSG Demo, which is the alias for this Security Group, give it a name, NSG SN01 Demo, just because it's going to be added onto subnet 01.
Location, when we take and copy here, we see that it comes with example and location, so if we take this one away, then we see that we get ours, so we can write location.
In the same way with Resource Group, we take a dot down here, and then we take a name. Then we have all the information that is correct here.
We have location of the Resource Group, we have a Resource Group name.
Then we come to the Security Group, as we have seen, and then we can say that, okay, we can call the rule for Allow, we can write public IP.
The priority is the rule, or the numbering it comes on, the higher the number, it will be from 100 to 4090-something.
Of course, if you have, it's important to think about how to place it in the rule, because if you have a rule that gets a hit before another, that rule will take effect first.
So, for example, if we get a rule that does not allow it, then it will be valid, and it will never come down to the one that allows it, for example.
Then we say here that we take it, it should be inbound, that is, into this subnet and this Network Security Group.
Allow, protocol TCP, we're going to test if it's RDP or SSH, it doesnt play such a big role.
Source Port Range, we can specify, for example, whether it should be 22 or 3389, but if we just let it be the stars, then it takes all, and then we will be able to define what addresses are allowed to be connected.
Destination Port Range, that's where you're allowed to connect, because in this Network Security Group, it can be on a subnet that has many machines on the inside,
then it may just be necessary to define what machine, this rule, should be valid for, that is, who you want to try to contact.
Because then we can say, okay, try to contact a web service here, then everyone is allowed to try to contact someone else, then no, then no one is allowed.
Source Address Prefix, here we can add something.
With Source Address Prefix, yes, it would then say what this address is, what the address is trying to connect to, and then it would be my private address,
and then you can go to whatismyipaddress.com and then you get that.
Destination Address Prefix would be the address for my attempt to connect to.
Tags, just remove it in the first round, then we see something like this, and then we have to remember that now we have to add the IP address, which is the public address.
So then we can go.
So if I go to whatismyipaddress and find it, I just take it with me with that address.
Then I enter it in Source.
Here we could have had, for example, if I had a larger network, then we could include the whole network.
And there is also the possibility to also set, for example, commas to allow more IP addresses.
So here we have Destination Address Prefix.
We don't need to define anything for everyone, but we could later specify what the machine should be.
And then we are on the next resource that we will have with us, and that is Group Association.
Then we see here, here it is Network Subnet, Network Security Group, Security Rule, and here we have Association.
We just take it with us, paste it in, and then we see here that we must have Subnet ID, and then we have to, let's see, we take this demo ID, because then we get to know that it is set up.
In addition, we also have Network Security Group, which we then take NSG.ID.
So, then the Azure Subnet Network Security Group Association again,
take effect after we have created the security group.
And then it will add the subnet ID when the subnet is set up.
If I just save the file, I can now run a, let's see, if we then take a Terraform plan, let's see, out, NSG plan.tf plan.
We run it in just to plan that we have resources, and then we take it with us to operate the virtual machine afterwards.
And when we have run the plan, then we see that we get an overview of what resources should be created, and then we have here Security Rule, and Security Group Association, and Network Security Group, and so on.
And then we see here Plan 2 to add, then we just run Terraform, apply, and then we take NSG plan.tf.
My mistake, writing error
Then we run through here, apply, and deploy these resources.
Then we will now create the machine and test that we get connected to it.
Okay, then the resources are created.
Then we are getting started with building up a fairly simple and nice infrastructure.
Then of course we must have some of the resources that should run on the inside here, and then we can very well find that we are going to build a virtual machine that will be part of this infrastructure.
So then we just go to the documentation we need.
Instead of Network Security, we write Virtual Machine.
So now we can see here that we have, if we go to azurerm_virtual_machine, then we want to see here that ut has been superseded, so it will be outgoing, because it will be replaced by azurerm_linux_virtual_machine and azurerm_windows_virtual_machine.
And then it's okay to just take these at once, so that we can get familiar with the coming and future way to create the virtual machine instead of using the deprecated way.
So then we can for example press here now, we think that, okay, we try a Linux virtual machine.
And then we can see here that we get an example of how we can create it.
We can scroll through disclaimers, here we see that there are some notes, notes, notes in this register, and known issue with the public IP address.
So we try a public IP address, we can see if we might encounter any of these challenges, and then we decide if we should do that.
So what we can do then is that we are going to build a Linux machine.
Here we see that we have our resource group, we have our network, we have our subnet, we do not have a network card, because we have to create that, we need a network card.
We do not have a network card, and a virtual machine must have it, because a network card is a resource in Azure, and in addition we also need an IP address that we can use for this virtual machine.
We can first make sure that we are going to set up an IP address, and then we can start by taking that we need the network interface, which is a resource for the virtual machine.
And then we can take it into the VS code, we put it in here, and then we write for example, NIC demo, and then we can just write that this is going to be NIC demo-limux.
And then we see here, for example, we have to remove that again, and then location, and then we take a name, IP configuration, internal, that's fine,
Azure RMS subnet, we have to set it like that, ID, private IP address, location, dynamic, that's fine.
Then we have to have a, we have to create our virtual machine, and here we see that it uses a public key for how we can log in to it.
For the sake of simplicity, we also need to use it, we can see how we can do it with a user name password instead in this virtual machine.
Oh, I almost forgot, we also have a public IP address, ID, but we haven't created it yet, so we have to create it first.
So if we hover here now, write resource, Azure RM public IP, like that, and then we can write pip public IP demo, and then we write here name pip demo-limux.
Of course we haven't had a numbering or anything like that, but we only have one we have to create.
And then we also have to have more information here, so if we go back to the documentation, we take and write public IP, and then Azure public IP,
we see here public IP, name, resource group, it must be inside for how, yes, it just has to know what resource group it's supposed to be in.
We take and copy, like that, and then we see RG name, like that, then we have location, location, and then we have allocation method, and there we can write static or dynamic,
we can write static now, then we get the same IP address every time we get on the machine, if we have dynamic, then we have to add a new IP address every time.
It doesn't really matter alot, we can extract this IP address afterwards, which we have to do to get permission to, so to speak, when we add this resource on another resource,
then it will get an address that we can collect afterwards, so we know how to connect to it.
So then we have created this resource, then we have this one, and then we can write public IP address, and then we go to that one, and like that.
Then we can deploy these resources here as well, or we can just throw the virtual machine at it at once, but as we said, we want to see how we can just use a username and password,
SSH into a Linux machine with a username and password, then we let it run and run with the certificates.
Then we can look back at the documentation for AzureRM Linux virtual machine, scroll down, then we see here that we are not going to add admin SSH key,
but if you look here, here we have the following arguments that are supported, admin username, and then we scroll down, and then we come out to admin password,
and what is important to remember when we come to admin password, when admin password is specified, disabled password authentication must be set to false,
and that's because if not, it will not allow us to use any other password.
And then we see that an admin password or admin SSH key must be specified, because it should be possible to log on this machine.
So now we're trying to put together a version of this resource that will be username and password to log in.
Then we go here, paste it in, then we see that it will be an Ubuntu server, here we can also see that admin SSH key, we don't want that with us,
and then we can look here at the resources of admin username, then we can write admin password, then we can write something just to have a password that we are going to use,
and then we can take and write the one we have to see there, we have to remember that, and then name, then oops, location, save it, then we can take a terraform format to get everything aligned,
and then we remember from the documentation that if we were to use another password, then we must have disabled password authentication, it must be set to false,
then it looks like we should have what we need in place to be able to deploy this virtual machine.
It is not a good practice to have this text in clear text, but we do it for ease of use to test that it should be implemented.
So then we now have the network interface, or first we have the public IP network interface, IPConfig network interface, and then we have to have here,
let's see, network interface, let's see, network interface dot, machine network interface, and then what have we called it, yes we called it for NIC demo,
so then it can not be an example, but we have to put it like that, then we can write terraform plan out nic vm tfplan, then we can see what it says, if it approves all the input we have come with,
and when we run through our plan, then we see here now that it has three resources that we have to add, then we can scroll up and see what is put, yes network interface,
then it is the virtual machine, and then we have an IP, public IP that will be used, IP address, known after apply, then we have to find it when we have added this resource to the machine,
and it has been started up, then we want to see what we get, because it is a bit of an Azure function, it has no IP address as long as the machine is not running, and then it has to be put on, but then we run a terraform, apply, and then nic vm plan,
then we just let it run up and update the resources, and then we want to see that here we have then been able to create all the resources that we have defined in our terraform plan,
then we can quickly see in the Azure portal how it looks like, then I can see here now that I have my RG demo vnet, where I have also got all the resources, here is an example machine,
here we can see I forgot to give the virtual machine a new name, and then we have our vnet, then we have the public address, so if I click on pip, the public IP now, then I can see here that I have a new IP address that I can connect to this machine,
then we can see here, associated to, nic demo linux, virtual machine, example machine, my bad, I forgot to give it a new name, and then we can now see how you can get this information from the command line, so that you can get this public address,
so now we just go to the vscode again, then we remember terraform, terraform state list, there we see, now we have our AzureRM linux machine, so then we can take terraform state show, we copy that with us,
then we list out all the information there, so if we scroll up here, then we see there, public IP address, and then we have that available there, so then something will happen, so if we go back to the Azure portal, then we can see now that we have our NSG, so if we click on NSG, then we can see under inbound security rules, allow public IP,
then we can see here that it is allowed, source range, any, any, and allow, so then we can see that we now, then if we click on terminal, if we use windows, then we can download putty, or something like that, to use SSH, and then we can, I can put a link in the description that makes it possible to download putty, but then we can write here now that I want SSH,
and then we take, let's see, I took to change, I would of course have put a different user name there too, but like that, then we enter the public address there, like that, and then yes, and then we have to enter our password, that probably didn't work, let's see, there, then we are in,
and now we see that now we have logged in a virtual machine in Azure with SSH, and it has only been allowed because the public address has been entered in the NSG, which means that it is allowed to enter, so if others try something against this IP address of the machine, then they would not enter, since they did not like the NSG as allowed to be linked.
So if we say, for example, write something in config, just to see here, then we see here that this machine has a local address on 10.0.1.4, which mirrors the subnet it is on, we do not see the public address, no, because it is a mapping between the public address and the internal address, or the machine, or Azure, makes sure that when we connect to the public address, then we are connected to this Linux VM.
So then we have set up a little fun infrastructure, we have a resource group, we have a VNet, we have a subnet, we have a network security group, we have a public IP address, we have a network interface, we have a virtual machine that has connected this network interface with this public IP address, and we have done this only with code, so we could deploy this as fast as possible, as many places as we wanted, just by changing different things, for example, there should be some other name or some place.
So it is a very quick introduction to how we can deploy code via Terraform, infrastructure via code we use Terraform. Of course, we will look more at how we can use variables and the like to make this Terraform infrastructure more flexible.
But as I said, we must always remember that now we have a part of the resources that are here, especially the virtual machine, if it is running here, then it is very stupid, because it will take away the resources.
So now I'm done with my testing, now I've seen that I can get up all the network, I can get up my security resources, I can get up the virtual machine, and then I can run a Terraform destroy, as I told you before, we have Terraform apply destroy, which we can also use, or we can also just write destroy.
If we write Terraform destroy now, then we will be prompted with, I'm sure you want to do this, and I do, because now I'm done with my testing, I just want to move and remove everything together, so I'm sure that this is not using any money, because then we have both the VM, the network security group, the public IP, and everything that is using money together.
If we write yes, then we are going to scroll up there, then we see everything together, destroyed, destroyed, network destroyed, subnet destroyed, resource group, vnet will be destroyed, so then we can just write yes to that, then we let Terraform do the job of just removing everything here, so we don't have to think any more about it. Here it says 8 resources to be destroyed. Perfect!
And after a little while, we will see that some of the resources are destroyed, so then we can check this in the Azure portal, if we go to resource groups, we can refresh here, we see that the resource group is gone, and then all the resources are gone, so we don't have to think about the cost that generates.
That's what I'm going to go through in this video and module here, so we will later look at further use of variables and similar techniques to make our code as flexible as possible.