Okay, in this video, we're going to take a look at the modules.
We're going to take a super simple, small example, just to try and get an idea of what the modules are.
And how we can use them, and how we can send information between the modules and up to the root module.
Simply explained, a module is actually a folder with a set of terraform files inside it, which has a certain configuration.
We can call this terraform configuration by using the module block in main.tf, and we can also generate output from some of these sub-modules,
which is information we need to use in the root module or other sub-modules.
So, in the example I'm going to go through now, I have created under module 4 now, a resource group folder, a storage account folder, and a main.tf file in sub-module 4.
So, I have my main.tf file under module 4 folder, and I have two folders under module 4 folder, resource group and storage account.
Of course, we can discuss whether it is appropriate to have your own folder for a resource group.
Of course, we should actually have the resource group in the same folder as the storage account,
and then we can set up the storage account, the resource group for the storage account, together with the storage account,
and possibly specify which resource group it should be, but this is to make it simple,
presented and demonstrated what we mean by modules and how we can send information between them.
We take the simple version first, and then we build ourselves out of more complex infrastructure modules,
as we see how we have done it through this first.
So, what we start with is that we then operate under the resource group folder, or first we have the main.tf file,
remember to have the terraform block with required providers,
and then we have azurerm and provider block with the features block.
When we have done that, we go to the resource group, set up a main.tf and a variables.tf.
When we find the main.tf, we will then set up the resource group.
Let's start here, in the main.tf to the resource group, we take and find the one we want,
find the resource group in registry, then we can scroll down here, and take the one we want,
this is known, we can also copy from another file, like that.
Before we make any changes to the main.tf now, we go to variables,
where we then create the variables, i.e. name and location, which we will use.
Under variables, we then write here variable, and then we write what the name of the variable should be.
If we create an empty variable here, then we can have a type of string, and then we can write a descriptor.
The descriptor should in this case be something that I want this variable to be used
as a common name for all resources. If I call it, for example, for basename,
in addition, I can now write that this should be something like that.
Then we, because we now add one string, which should be, like,
be there to identify the resources and the resource group.
In addition, we also need, of course, a location, variables, empty variable, location, string, like that.
Let's just save that. When we have done that, we go to main.tf again,
we take location, we just write var.location, then on name.
The suggestion that came up now was that it should be a string,
because it is a string we are going to use, so we have quotation marks.
The dollar sign to show that here comes a variable that will be merged, curly brackets,
and then we add on, for example, that there should be a resource group.
It depends on how you want to name this. Some name conventions are that
what resource it is comes first, possibly it is a resource group, then you write it rg, etc.
And then you have storage account, and then vnet, subnet, or sn, etc.
So in that way, you have a name behind, with a follow-up, maybe location,
and then if there should be more and the like.
If you want to see how this is done, or want tips,
on how to name such a resource in Azure, there is of course a name convention
that you can go to in Azure. So if we just search under Microsoft Azure's
documentation and naming convention, so define your naming convention,
then we see here that we get a suggestion on how we can name our resources.
And here, for example, pip is a public IP, what the public IP is connected to,
i.e. workload, if it is prod, location, and instance number.
So if we scroll down, we will get a suggestion for a lot of different resources,
how we can name them. Here we have virtual network gateway, how we can name them,
site-to-site, VPN connections, routing table, virtual machines, etc.
So if you are going to build a naming convention in Terraform's infrastructure,
then you can take the starting point in, for example, this naming convention.
Of course, naming conventions are often defined by the place you work,
or the infrastructure you are going to set up, so you just have to follow the
same one that you might be working with, or you can start and define
the naming convention you are going to use, if it is a completely new infrastructure
that is going to be built. So back to VS Code. There are several ways to do this,
if we, for example, take and write rg-%s, and then we can do like this, or we can also use
format, which means format, and then we can see, then we have rg-%s, and then not like that,
no, what it does here now, it formats the same string, we can show that from the
documentation page to Terraform, how to find it, if we search for string functions format,
then we can show how to format the strings, for example, then we can see down here that we
find syntax for the use of %s, and for example, %s, what does that mean? Yes, %s converts
the string and inserts the string's characters. So what we do is that we format the rg
string, and then add on var.base_name to it. So there are several ways to take custom
names in this context, but we can choose one and use them. We can, regardless of being
smart and double-checking in the Terraform console afterwards, that you get your content and
content, or your name, and the way you want your name to be. I just change it. I use,
back to the practice I have used, that I have the name of the resource I want first,
so I use to define it as resource group, or storage account, or whatever it is that comes first,
so it's easier to see what it is. Then we just save the main.tf file from resource group,
and then we just save it in the work. What we then have to do is go to the main.tf. It is important
that we have several main.tf files, one that is under resource group, and then we have one
that is under module 4. So if I go now to the main.tf, which is in what we call the root module,
then we can now call up the module with a module block. And then we see here, it comes with a
proposal that I have to call up the module by using a name. So if I write resource group,
and then we can say here that we write source, resource group, base name, then we can for example
write what the base name should be. Location should then be base name, it can then be Terraform,
demo, tf.demo, then that name will be added to all of the resources and the input of what I'm going to
use together with base name. You have to remember that this dot slash source is then that you are in the
existing folder and go to resource group folder. Source is then dot, which means the existing folder,
the existing folder, which is module 4 in this case. And then slash, which is up to resource group,
and this is a kind of form for Linux or what is known as how the file structure is in the Linux world.
For Windows, we are used to that there is such a type of reference to the track, but we will then
use this type. So standing in the folder, we have had several sub-folders here, so we have had to refer
to it or something like that. So there is source, standing in the folder and down to resource group. Just
put it in. Just run a Terraform init just to see. So we see that it runs successfully.
When Terraform init is run, we can now write Terraform plan out main tf plan.
So we see what happens. And then we see here that the location is correct. And then we see that the name
will then be the name we had put in base name and location plus what is in front of base name.
Now we see that we care a little about if we can, of course, and we will of course use
variable file and so on. This was just to show how we then picked up that module for resource group.
And then we can now then further add on what we have with storage account. So what we do then,
that we go to storage account, create a main.tf. We go to the main.tf. So under main,
then we will then create a storage account. So then we can then just go and find it in Terraform
documentation. So there, storage account, resource. So we might think, oh, what's the difference
in doing this? Now we have learned a lot about how we should do it with variables and everything
together that has more good practice to do it. But as I said, I do it just to show
examples with modules, then we will of course take and use these different techniques we have
gone through earlier to make it as flexible as possible with our infrastructure.
Go to the variable file, write var, empty variable, storage account name, type string,
like that. And then we will have one. So we add to rg name. And then finally we add to location.
So there we have created the variables. And then we go and create all these files. But there is one
thing that we should perhaps address at once, and that is the storage account name. The storage
account name must be global unique. So therefore we should add on a, which I have done manually
every time, just write random number back. We can also use a random generated string tf.
And then we need a random generator, or we need the provider to provide this randomization.
So if we go back to Terraform, search for random, then we see here, here it says random,
click on use provider, take it with us there. Then we can now look at the documentation. The random
provider has the random Terraform configuration. Let's see, yes, that's fine. And then we just take
that to the main.tf file. And then the main.tf file, then I mean the main.tf file for
storage account. As I said, it can be a bit complicated with a lot of files, but we can do it.
Put the provider in the top there. We don't need that one there. There we do that. Let's save it.
When we have done that, we then have to add to the random block, or a resource, which is a random
block. So if we then start with resource, and then we can write random, the resource is
underscore string. Then we can just call it random string. Yes, so let's see. Here we have
what the values that are related to this random string are. So if we then take length,
then we can now say that it should then be, for example, six. And then we can have special
characters. We don't want that with special characters, because it is unwanted for a storage account.
It has lower letters and numbers that I want. In addition, upper, set it false, because upper
characters are either not supported in the name of a storage account. Then of course we have to change
what is here. And one way we can do it, then, is like we did last time. Dollars,
curly brackets, there, and then we take base, no, var.base_name, and then we
have to add another variable, and then we see that we have to end the curly brackets, and then a
new dollar, curly brackets, and random_string.random_string.result. What this does is that it
puts together, let's see, one too many of these, that it puts together the base name that we
give as a variable, together with the random string that is generated by the resource random string.
And then we see that we dont need to specify all the time the random generated names that we have
done. In addition, we can add, for example, SA or whatever, but now we're thinking, yes,
we just use the base name that we take for the storage account, because that is something that we
specify in the storage account. Let's see, yes, here we write, base name, like that, then we are
done. Oh yes, and one more thing, which I forgot in the beginning when we wrote this, it was that the base name
can actually be added that someone gives it big letters, or uppercase letters, and then we can
add on here now that we want this to be in lower, so that there won't be something wrong
with the name. So if we were to write lower, and then we just take and do one like that, and one like that,
then it would force the base name to be lowercase. But we might start wondering what
we have base name in, both in variables here, and then we have base name in variables here. But what we have to
remember is that what is in each folder belongs to the configuration for each folder, or module,
and then I want to say that the base name here belongs to what is set up in the storage account,
and the base name that we have in here is also what belongs to the resource group. Again, a little stupid to
usually set up a resource group together with the resource, but it is now just to get two simple
and very small things to relate to, which makes it perhaps easier for us to get hold of it, and then we can
build on it later. So what we have done then, that we have set the name to be a lower case with a
random string, but resource group name, we also have var.resource group name, location, we have var.location,
tags, we don't need right now. So save everything, remember to do so. So what we can do now,
is that we go to our main.tf on the root level, so under module 4, this is what we have
done, and now we have to add the modules block again, and then we take and write here storage account,
and then source, it will be ./StorageAccount, and then we have variable base name, name, I like, and then we can
write in what we want here, and then it can, for example, be anything here, then write TF demo with
large letters, or just like that, to show that we see that the variable here takes it down to lower case
But then comes a question, we can then take, because this one has to be set up under a resource group name,
and what is the challenge here now, we want to do that, or we can now see, it comes with a proposal here,
with how we can get out module resource group rg name, and that is one way, but we thought, we
should look at how we can use output now, just to see that, okay, we can send information
from the resource group module, over and up to the root module, see, go to the resource group,
create a new file, outputs.tf, under here, we create a new output, and then we call it in for rg_output, for example,
or we can take with the name, the value should then be what the resource group is from this one, and then we see that
we did not give it a name, so it will suggest example here now, so Azure resource group example name,
so if you look at the resource that we set up, then we would have just let it stand for example here,
we should of course give it a name, something that we can reuse later instead of using example,
but that was what was set up now, so then we just take it to stand for value,
Azure rm resource group example dot name, that is the name of the resource group,
go to main.tf, and then we can see here that it is the resource group module that runs first,
and then we can now write that we want to use module dot resource group dot rg name out,
because this is the one we picked up, so if we then look back at the resource group,
outputs, rg name outputs, that is the one that is sent from the resource group module, and then we have
the one we want to have as resource group name, for example, we can now write location,
we see, we should of course, again, this is for the example, the location, we give it several times,
the DRY principle, don't repeat yourself, yes, I agree, so the thing is that you just have to check here now,
that we actually get this to flow, that it operates the resource group, gets the resource group name output
in the storage account, and then we have the storage account that is set up based on a random
generated string that is added along with the base name, which should be lowercase, and then it will be
set up, yes, it will be set up as a resource group and a storage account, so go to main.tf at the top level,
type terraform init, make sure that you get the random provider, when we follow up with that,
terraform plan out main.tf plan, oops, two errors, the first one we can see,
rgname is required, okay, I got the resource group name, sorry, like that, and then it says location is required,
I forgot to save the file, like that, now I saved the file, let's start over, terraform plan,
when the plan is run, we see here, three to add, see what you actually want to do,
scroll up to the top, resource group will be set up with rgtftmo, which is the base name,
and the resource group, which I set up first, storage account, and what we can see now,
which is different to earlier, is that name known after apply, it is because we don't know the names
before, or to the storage account before they have run the random string generation in addition,
so that will be run when we apply it, so that if we now run then, and terraform apply main.tf plan,
we see that the resources are beginning to be prepared, when apply is done, then we can now see
right here, here it says at the end, tfdemo, and then a random generate string, which is to
give a unique name to the storage account, so that it does not fail to create the storage account,
now we have three resources added, we can now go to the Azure portal, under storage account,
we see here that we have rg-tf-demo, which is the resource group with the base name,
below that, we also see that we have the storage account with tfdemno, always lowercase,
and random string pn4ur6 behind, which of course I have selected several types, we specified that we
wanted to have six random generated characters behind our base name, so we could have specified that we
we actually get an 8. We could do that if we go to the storage account main.tf.
Then we remember that we have specified the lengths.
And then we see that our resources and our resource group have been set up.
And we have received that we have picked up outputs from module.resourcegroup.rgname.output,
which means that we can then use it later.
So then we have come through the setup of our used modules for our own part,
so that we can have several smaller parts to work with,
so that we can have, for example, the network in one place,
other types of resources in one place, and then we work separately with them,
and then put it together in another main.tf configuration.
So that is part of the principle of breaking down everything in smaller parts
that we work with to make it as flexible as possible.
Then we have our own configuration with the file for a resource collection
that we want to reuse later, we can just take that folder.
And as always, before we finish, we run a terraform destroy
to remove all the resources that we do not need to be in Azure.
Confirm with yes, three resources destroyed.
Confirm in the portal that it is removed.
Here we see under resource groups,
here we have no resource or resource group with that name.
And that was all I wanted to go through with this video.
This was just an introduction to modules,
how to use multiple folders with multiple separate config files,
and then you can see how we can put this together in a more complex environment afterwards.