In this video, we will now start the use of GitHub and GitHub Action.
I now have a finished terraform configuration with a static web page.
We have already gone over what that is.
That means that we will now use GitHub, and we will then set up a GitHub Action that will contain a trigger that will deploy this infrastructure.
I can just quickly go through this setup of the static web page.
In the main, we have some locals that will say that it determines if we are in a workspace, which will then set up such a workspace suffix if we are to deploy these resources.
If it is not in a workspace, that is, if it is default, then it should not have any workspace suffix.
The resource group name will then be that you see if the terraform workspace is default or not.
If it is default, it only takes the variable as the resource group name.
If it is a workspace that is set, then it takes the resource group name plus the suffix, which makes it easier to see what environment you are working with when you see the resources in the Azure portal afterwards.
For that, I would say that if we operate the resource group name, then we do rg-name and then bind-devstage or prod.
In the same way, we do that with the storage account.
Then we take the storage account and then we give it a variable name and then we set up a local space suffix.
I see now that I have forgotten, of course, to check if the workspace is default or not, because we also have to have it on the Azure portal.
So then it is in place and then we see here that it checks if the workspace is there.
So, check the workspace and if not, then it also takes the variable name plus local suffix.
Of course, we also have to have a random generation of a string here, so that we get a unique name in Azure.
What this does is operate a resource group with the name that is based on the processing here in local.
Location is then from var location, variable location.
The name will then be lower on the storage account and what is set in local for the storage account plus random string.
Check the resource group, check location, standard, lrs, set up a static web page on the storage account.
Set up a web or a dollar web that has a specific purpose for hosting static webpages.
Source content then looks at the variable content for source content and then we add local web suffix.
Here we also see that we should have had, if it does not have a workspace here,
then we see that the web suffix here will be empty if it is not there or maybe default if it is not in there.
So here we should also have set in that, for example, the web suffix should be something else if it is not in any workspace.
But if we just leave it there, then we see what the variable will be, because it will just be yours, combined with the web suffix.
Okay, the output is then the web site address, this is a reference.
And then we have the in-app provider, so I still use the backend that I have set up earlier.
I also have here standard, therefore, record providers, etc.
And then the provider manager and features, the obligatory block.
What is important to consider when we are going to push this to Git and use Git of Action to deploy this,
is that our TF storage file is something that we do not want to take over to GitHub.
Therefore, I have now taken my variables file, where I have put in default values, which is included,
and that will be included over to GitHub, which has content that is default value.
Of course, there are things that can be sensitive, should not be included in default value,
and then you can of course mark it as sensitive true.
But in this round now, we will just test now that we get to the Git of Action first,
then we see how we can use the variables later.
Go over to my repo in GitHub, click on GitHub Actions.
When GitHub Actions has come out, we see here that we have a lot of deployments that are shown as examples.
Here we see Terraform, which can show us a workflow for Terraform.
We can also see that it is quite large and extensive, so we do not need to start with it in the first round,
but we can also see here that there are many other types of examples that we can use if we want to see.
What we do first, we set up a workflow yourself,
and when we click on it, we will see here that in this repository, a .github folder is created,
with a workflows folder underneath it, and then we get a yaml file underneath it.
What this map means, I have included in the description for this video,
because then it would be, if I were to go through all the theories for everything that is discussed,
or go through in the video, then it will be a very long video.
So what I name this file here, it is a bit dependent on what I am going to use it for,
but since we can go back to my GitHub, I have called it here for staticwebpage,
no, website, which is under module 6.
I can now just call it here for staticwebsite, yaml,
then I will now fill in yours with information.
So now I have just pasted in here a very simple workflow to go through it,
and then see that we get to publish or deploy this infrastructure with GitHub Actions.
As you can see in the description, or in the comment field here,
there is a basic workflow that helps you to start with GitHub Actions.
The workflow must have a name.
Then there will be something that is dependent on what happens when this trigger is running,
and what I want is that the trigger for this should be dependent on the changes
that come or when it is pushing changes to this map in my repo.
Because I do not want that everything, or if the trigger, for example, is that the main is pushed,
then it will all the time be triggered that it will deploy, deploy, deploy.
This is something I wanted to test with this map, and this infrastructure that is on this map.
So if I now, for example, go back to this one, and then start to change something
inside this configuration file here, and then push it to GitHub,
then that will be the trigger for something to happen with this infrastructure.
Because one can say that as long as something has been pushed to the repo,
then that will be the trigger.
But we have a lot of configuration in here,
which we do not want anything to happen with every single time this is triggered.
Or we do not want this deployment of a static web page to be triggered
every time some changes are made in any of these other maps.
We want this configuration to only be retained, what is in that map.
So therefore, we have that the trigger is the changes that are pushed to the path
course material module 6 static website.
It is also allowed that this can be run manually from GUI.
So when the job is to be run, then there will be something, of course,
that must process and execute this job.
And then we spin up an Ubuntu.
We spin up an Ubuntu that then operates a job,
as it is called for web.
And here we see that it has specified the environmental variables,
which are Azure Client ID, Azure Client Secret, Azure Subscription and Azure Tenant.
In addition, I have also had a working directory,
because I want Terraform to be executed in the working directory,
so that it does and executes the actions on the correct map.
So we come to the steps, what is it supposed to do?
Yes, it is supposed to perform a checkout.
Checkout means that it copies the repository content over to its place,
so that the Ubuntu machine can actually access the file and execute what it is supposed to do.
Actions and checkout, I'll come back to that.
We'll find it in the Marketplace.
This is, I think, maybe a V4 or something.
So what we do afterwards is that we run a Terraform command,
because we now want to use Terraform to execute these transactions.
I could of course have added a name to this checkout,
that it has got a name in the same way that all the steps here could have got a name,
so that you can easily see it in the GitHub user interface afterwards.
So afterwards, it's actually just familiar information from before.
Here we run Terraform init, which means that it builds up back-end,
ensures that it has a place where it stores state files,
and the state file would then be Azure.
The storage account, where we have a container called TFState,
then put a file there, because we remember that if we go back,
we see Prider on our static file.
Here we refer to the resource group that we have had before for the state file,
the storage account, also the container name,
and also what key we are going to use.
I can double-check now, just by going to the resource groups on the tenant I use.
Here is rgbacon.tfstate.
Then I can look at the storage account.
I have cleaned up this a bit before, but you can of course overwrite the files,
which is there with a new configuration when you deploy a new one.
Here is the container, and here I only have back-end files for Terraform,
I mean, Terraform state files for my back-end that will host this one.
So now afterwards, I will get a web Terraform TFState,
depending on what name I have set here.
And then I can continue the deployment by running Terraform plan,
which we are familiar with.
Terraform plan on working directory.
Then I run a Terraform apply on working directory with auto-approve,
because I can not give any input after I have sent everything here over to Ubuntu,
which is going to perform this task.
So then I can easily now just commit the changes like this,
and then create static-website-yaml.
Perfect, I'll do that.
And then we see that we have set up our first GitHub workflow in GitHub.
If we now go to Terraform, no, to our VS Code,
then it is now set up that there should be a trigger that is performed based on the changes in this file.
I can now first go to source control,
I can now also pull, so that I can get all the last information.
And then we see here that under the top here now,
there is a GitHub folder with workflows and static-website-yaml.
It means that it is, as I said, under the root,
so that this static-yaml file was the one we set up instead in GitHub.
So now we have all these files that we have in GitHub repo and in the VS Code.
If we now go back here,
what we are going to do is try to trigger the whole GitHub,
GitHub action with changes that are made in static-website.
I have in my main file here now, I have made some changes that have not been saved.
So if I, for example, now,
make this one go to GRS, Global Redundant Storage,
then I save it.
When I save it, source control will now see that there is a change in the file here,
which makes it possible to push these changes to GitHub.
Now we see, source control says that there is a change here that I want to be committed.
I can now first go to GitHub and look at my GitHub action again,
that it has set up a GitHub action workflow called web.
So if I click on it, I can see here that this has not been run yet.
So you can see now, if we continue to trigger this, we will also take deploy, web,
GRS, GRS.
This is the first deployed menu, but if it has already been deployed,
then we can just sync changes.
And then we can go over to our GitHub web,
then we take a little refresh on it.
And then we see here that deploy, web.
Click up.
It is then pushed by me.
And it is the main.
And then we can now go into the job.
So we see here.
Here we see static-website, YAML, on push.
Then we see what happens further down.
And then we can see here that all steps that are made,
which is in the YAML file, will be first checked out.
Then we run the GitHub, no, Terraform init,
which we also see that we know from before,
because it has an init of the backend.
Then we see here initializing provider plugins,
go through what is there, Terraform is successfully initialized.
Then we run a Terraform plan.
And then we see here how the resources are set up.
And this is also known to us from the VS code.
Then we see here plan for to add.
And then run it through Terraform apply.
And then it starts to deploy these resources, of course.
And then we see what is happening now.
Where is Terraform apply?
It is now, and then push out these resources,
based on my change in the repo on VS code.
That I changed something here.
Committed it, pushed it over to GitHub,
which then started the deployment of this one.
Because we have set that these and these Terraform commands
should be run through a workflow,
when a change is made in this map.
And then we also have primary with endpoints.
We had an output from this Terraform configuration,
which would show us the URL to this static web page,
which is in this storage account,
after it has run is finished.
Then we are post run action and complete job.
So now it has run through all this work,
which makes it can quickly check in Azure.
And in Azure, if we take a refresh here,
then we see that now we have RG Web.
Under RG Web, we have the storage account,
which has then received SA Web random generated name.
And then under the storage account,
there is, as we will add, a static web page website.
And under static web page, we have the URL here.
This can be seen back on the deployment,
that under Terraform Apply,
at the bottom there, we have it.
So if we press this one, it will open a web page.
Note that it takes a little time before this page actually comes up,
or if the job is finished,
so if you go in on the page too early,
then you can just get this application,
or something that is in production.
Here we see that it got with default,
since it was what it was,
so it was not really,
you can of course change it so that you do not get with default,
but here we have at least performed a deployment,
using GitHub Actions.
But now we have applied and deployed this infrastructure,
but what we want to do now,
or what we have done throughout the course,
is that we destroy here when we are done testing.
Because there was just a test use of a static web page,
with no use of workspaces.
So this is one single stage,
or one single environment that is deployed.
So we want to remove this now.
But as we can see now on our GitHub workflow,
what triggers this workflow,
what does the workflow contain?
Yes, this is just that there will be a change to this map,
and then we have a workflow dispatch,
it does not say anything below here,
but it allows us to run it from the GitHub repository.
And here we also have the terraform steps that will be done,
all the steps in it, plan, apply.
And as you can see,
here is missing a step that we may be familiar with from before.
We have to do something about it.
So before we edit this file.
So if we start the workflow dispatch,
as I said, I put a link where you can find information
about everything that goes through here now,
so you can just take the theory in the video.
So what we can add,
is an input that is required to determine
what is to be done when this trigger happens.
So here we see, we have added a workflow dispatch,
we have added an input.
We have an action type,
that is, what action should be performed.
And then there is an apply or destroy,
which we want to do here.
This input is required,
and then of course we set a default to apply,
so that if we do not give it an input,
then it is applied.
The last thing we have to change,
that is what happens in the bottom row here.
Because here we have terraform apply,
and then you have to enter an if,
and then you see here that
GitHub event input action type,
if it is not applied,
then it will run terraform apply auto approve,
and in working directory.
And here we see, if terraform,
or the name terraform destroy,
so GitHub event input action type,
is like destroy,
then it will run terraform destroy auto approve.
So then it would say that it runs through terraform,
into terraform plan,
but when it comes further now,
to the steps we saw earlier,
then it will decide based on the input,
if it actually should run apply,
is it not an input,
default apply,
is it an input,
then it can most likely be set to destroy,
because we want to delete it,
when we are done testing.
Then we just have to commit these changes,
update,
write that it was a input action that was set,
and when we have done this now,
then we can go back to our GitHub action,
and then we can look at web,
and here we see,
this workflow has a workflow dispatch trigger,
and then we can see here that,
now we have,
what action should be performed,
and then as I said,
apply as default,
let's see,
on workflow,
so that we have the opportunity to apply destroy here,
it has provided a nice way to do it,
if you want it to be manual,
through,
should it be in the production environment,
for example,
then we will see on the scene,
how we use it as a trigger,
that there will be a manual,
or a message,
that someone has to manually send to Eprod,
and here too,
it has provided a way to have,
that something is going to be destroyed,
if something is going to be destroyed,
then it is a manual operation,
that must be done,
so that you do not,
but for our test for tomorrow,
then it is a bit like,
not quite where we see ourselves,
that we want to be,
for now we just have to build up,
and tear down,
without too much manual,
then we will rather see,
when we set it up with environments,
that we must have a form for,
manual interaction,
to deploy to Eprod,
and not least,
destroy it,
so then we have to go back to,
to our file,
yaml file,
for static website,
understand,
remember to have,
yaml,
extension,
and not least,
you can also have a,
GitHub action,
extension,
which makes you see the actions,
in the VS Code,
I can write an observation,
of which extensions I use,
but what we have to do then,
this will be a manual trigger,
which we may not want to use,
for this purpose,
so what we can say then,
okay,
we want to make something,
a trigger,
that should be based on,
which commit message,
or message,
that is put in the commit,
so that if I,
for example,
make some changes,
in these files,
and then set the commit message,
to destroy,
then it will trigger,
that this will be destroyed,
so then I just take this away,
because then we have actually,
seen how it works,
and how we can use it,
and then we can now,
take away this,
I could even change this,
because I have already used it,
under deploy our resource groups,
so if we can just call this here,
for what else,
actually,
if it contains a single job call,
there is a picture,
but I call it for web,
and it is a deployment of web,
so what we write here,
we can just write,
terraform,
and then it is then,
what we should do then,
it was that we should check,
what happened,
with this,
because this would no longer be,
in hell,
here it is,
gone with this,
because this was based on,
the trigger we had instead,
with apply and destroy,
but it was a manual thing then,
so what we then have to,
put in here,
like this,
now we have put in a new step,
or a step,
in all our steps,
we have check out first,
terraform in terraform plan,
and then we have,
check last commit message,
so when it does check,
in the output,
or in the blog file,
which is for this commit,
so check it then,
if this message is destroy,
then it will run,
a terraform destroy,
if it is not a destroy,
so anything else,
then it would be,
that it contains,
auto,
or it would go through,
terraform apply,
auto approve,
and that's how we want it,
so now we can check it,
that we then also save,
the commit,
we take,
let's see,
so,
then we will update it here,
and then we can say,
that the message here,
should be that we have put,
what we have changed,
is a conditional run,
for terraform,
and then we just take,
and synchronize it out,
to our GitHub,
so that the workflow file,
is updated,
I mix a little,
between where I update the file,
sometimes in VS Code,
sometimes in GitHub,
web,
limit,
but you have to at least remember,
that if you do something,
in the web limit,
then you have to come back,
to the VS Code,
and push,
or pull down,
the changes,
that have been made here,
so if we then go to,
the workflow of ours,
then we can see here now,
that there are no workflows,
that are run through,
we can then,
try something,
if we manage to trigger,
this destroy,
based on the new,
changes of ours,
in Yammer file,
because we have,
RG Web,
which is here now,
and then we will go in here,
module 6,
static web,
we can go to main,
TF,
and here we can now change then,
that we will have a commit message,
which will destroy,
this infrastructure,
what this change is,
it can be that we just,
for example,
set a change,
from one or the other here,
or we can also just put in,
destroy,
like that,
so if I,
save it now,
then we see that we get a commit,
and then if I write,
destroy,
and we can check then,
what is the word,
that should be in the message,
yes,
it is destroy,
go out back,
and commit it,
and then we run a,
synchronization of it,
out to GitHub,
we can go to GitHub,
workflow of ours,
then you will see now,
that in a short time,
then this workflow will be triggered,
and it is called destroy,
and then we can see,
all of the steps,
as this workflow,
runs through,
and then we see,
that here,
has the check,
of the last,
committed message,
has been run,
and then we see,
that police has been,
that this is,
deprecated,
so there is another way,
to do it for now,
and then we have conditional run,
on Terraform,
action,
but,
conditional access mine,
was not quite,
as expected,
it did not do,
exactly,
what I had thought,
because here,
there is no change,
no object needed to be destroyed,
so that it,
most likely,
has not seen,
what it should have destroyed,
and then we have to go back,
and fix it,
and it can be,
as simple as,
that,
I have forgotten,
to take with,
which working directory,
this should be,
so that,
if something happens here,
it runs,
Terraform,
destroy,
but,
they do not know,
how to do it,
and therefore,
then we take,
and then put it,
in here,
look,
and,
so,
then we save it,
so we also take,
set,
that it should,
update,
working,
work,
dir,
kond,
run,
terraform,
action,
so,
because then,
we get updated,
that this conditional run,
is then,
in the working directory,
which is specified,
up here,
and then we can take,
and sync it out,
then we can take,
and then,
try to change,
again,
that we have a change,
in mine,
to our file,
destroy,
we save it,
go to the source console,
destroy,
like that,
commit it,
sync it,
then we go to our workflow,
if something happens,
under GitHub Actions,
that we have got a new destroy,
we would perhaps have called it a destroy v2,
just because we,
if something happens,
that a new one is being initiated,
then we can look at this,
deployment,
what actually happens,
by clicking on it,
then we just let it go,
then something can happen,
what is interesting here now,
what it is,
Conditional Run Terraform Actions,
I'm going to take a look at this,
please upgrade using environment files,
for the output,
then we take and do it,
and here,
we see that now,
it does something,
based on the conditional rules,
or the input it gets,
and then we see here,
that now,
a plan lag,
and destroy four resources,
so then we have now set up,
a GitHub repository,
with a resource,
which is deployed,
which we want to deploy,
and then we have prepared,
a workflow for this one,
which will then be initiated,
based on the changes,
into this file structure,
and then delete it,
by getting the input message,
destroy,
so then we have,
tested the first GitHub action,
looked at different conditions,
both manually,
and not least,
with input,
through the commit message,
and we have then deployed,
and then the website comes up,
and now destroy,
and then the website is gone,
so then we can check here,
that when it is running,
we can go to the portal,
then we see,
it is running,
job completed,
it is done,
cleaning up,
then we can see here,
under conditional,
that it has destroyed,
destroyed, destroyed, destroyed,
destroyed,
and everything is done,
destroyed completed,
we see in the resource group,
that it is now destroyed,
what is important to think about now,
so now we have a command,
or a comment,
which is called destroy,
if I remove it,
create a file,
commit it again,
then it will update,
these resources,
so now,
this is just a way to show,
how we then trigger this,
it is just to show,
now how we use a trigger,
and how it works,
with for example,
a commit message,
so the next time,
we create a commit,
and push it here,
to the repository,
then it will of course,
be updated,
and then we should of course,
remove this destroy,
comment,
so it is just a simple way,
to show,
that now this is destroyed,
so this static website,
does not exist in Azure,
but if I remove this now,
start making some changes,
create it,
and then I do not have,
destroy flag,
put in my code,
then it is running in Azure,
so that was it,
bought,
or bought and bought,
a little longer video,
about GitHub Action,
this time.