Okay, in the last video, we saw how we set up a dev, stage and prod environment
in Microsoft Azure with a static web page using Terraform.
And here we see that we have all three of our resource groups.
We have the backend resource group, which hosts all of the state files for these three environments.
And if we go into each of these resource groups, we see that we have the storage account
which is located with this static web page available for the environment.
If we open static web, we see here that we have the URL and that is the endpoint for this site and index.
So what we're going to do in this video is that we're going to see how we can push an change to such a site.
It was very simple. We saw here that we have made in Terraform, say, stage, dev, prod, etc.
So if I now want to make a change, I can, for example, very easily just change the content that is to be in this site and push it.
So if I now just take here and write del update del 1, then I take and paste it in.
Then I would get the opportunity to push it in.
Then just web content update del 1.
Then we jump back after we have synced these changes, then we can jump back to our GitHub.
Then we go back.
And if we go to action, we see here that now it has started a new trigger.
Or the trigger is that it has been changed, now the file in the repository for static web.
So when we then go to web content update del 1, we see here that now it will run through all the steps that we were used to and saw instead.
Now that everything is done, we see here that it took a few seconds.
Now I can just go to the stage or stageprod part here now just to check.
Because it's a bit like the test, what the test does is just to check if they are still there.
So this one will be approved as long as it is a website that responds.
Because it just wants to try to do curl against the web address or URL to this site.
And then if we just take this one with us just to show it.
So if we take curl like this, then we see that we get the content on the website.
So if we also take curl 100% vntnu.no, then we see that we get the content that is on that site.
So what you can do, you can use curl to run more extensive tests on what, for example, is the correct content there, the site comes up in the right way.
What we actually just do now is to show that we can make a test.
And as long as the test is checked, it jumps to the next step.
And that would be for our part.
Just check if it's a website on that stage.
Yes, it's a website.
Open to stageprod.
Is it a website on stageprod?
Yes, it's a website.
And then it goes into prod.
And there is the manual process where a person has to go in and actually review.
I can also go in and see what is actually happening.
So that's it.
And then we're going to see here under production.
Then we see that we see web content update part 1.
Then we see here that the content or changes that have been made are source content and default value of that.
And default value changes the update part.
And then I can go in and approve that, because it seems fine in this context.
I could also start all waiting jobs, since there is a possibility for that, since there is only one job waiting for me.
So, and then I deploy the website to production.
And that should go very fast, since it's just a change of source content to the website.
So what we're doing now, we're making very, very small changes with very small infrastructure.
Where we see that, yes, we're just running Terraform, yes, we're just running Tencent, yes, we're just updating the content.
But that's because we want to get tested here.
Simple now, just with simple infrastructure.
The process actually happens in it, because it's the Terraform or the infrastructure as a code, the thought process.
And the process we go through now, then something should happen, implement it here.
More infrastructure, more tests, etc., of course.
Since this will only be a demonstration of how we do it with GitHub Workflows, with GitHub Actions.
And there we see, the web point is checked, so if we then take, for example, TestBroad.
Here we also see that we need to update DLN, getWebEndPoint, since we want to have URN, we can now click on that.
And here we see that we get middle Terraform, CCD, update DLN.
We can see that we have just started updating the site speedruns here.
There we see that we have updated DLN.
There we have previously updated DLN, and there we have previously updated DLN.
So now we have Prod, Stage, Stage, and Dev.
Now we have three websites that we can relate to.
And test it with Dev, or develop it with Dev.
Test it in Stage, and then when it is verified and tested correctly in Stage, you can deploy it to Prod.
Of course, it is both tested on the Terraform code, tested on the infrastructure, and a lot that can be implemented on this type of CCD.
But that's more we'll come to afterwards.