Okay, then we're back. In this video, we're going to look a little more at the testing of our infrastructure code.
We have now been through Validate, that we look at how we can validate the infrastructure code,
the infrastructure we have developed with Terraform, but of course there are many different testing tools available to us.
Now we're going to look at another tool, i.e. TFSEC, which takes care of the security aspects of the infrastructure code that we have made.
TFSEC has gone over to a collaboration with a new actor, which makes them go away from the name TFSEC,
but it is still developing and supports Terraform, Azure and what we're going to look at there.
But most of it is just to show that there is this type of tool, and we can use GitHub Actions to run these tests via Workflows,
which makes it that we get a central place where we will keep these tests, so that everyone who runs these tests will get the same criteria being used.
I can first show here that I have installed TFSEC on my machine using Brew, but you can either use Brew or Chocolatey and install it on your machine.
There will be simple pointers in the links that correspond to this module.
So if we now take a look at my infrastructure, we can see here that I have now, I'm in my demo-infra folder,
and I have here the infrastructure that I have installed, which I have previously run the Validate test on,
and I have now created a GitHub workflow called TFSEC.
But first we can look at, if we go to this infrastructure that I have here,
if I go and run TFSEC here now in the existing folder, dot for the existing folder, or we can just run TFSEC for the folder we are in,
then it will look at all the Terraform configuration that is in this folder.
So if I run TFSEC, it will now see that Terraform, no, TFSEC, gives me quite a lot of output that I can take advantage of.
I can first, what I mentioned at the beginning, that, let's see, TFSEC is joining Trivy family, so it will continue to be available,
but it is starting to merge into Trivy. Here now, Trivy, Terraform, Azure, not up and running.
Therefore, it will continue to be there. So if we scroll all the way down, then we can start to see that we have received some messages about the type of tests that have been passed,
and what may be potential problems. In addition, we can look at this type of critical, or the level of problems that occur in the code,
and we can see here that it has found several different levels, i.e. from low to medium to high, and then it can now think that we can evaluate based on what it is that we should take a stance on.
So if I just take a position on one of these tests, then I can scroll up to the top and see what it starts with.
Here we see that we get a warning that the network itself does not block access by default, i.e. access control list on the storage account vault.
Azure Key Vault does not block access, does not have an ACL that blocks access by default.
What is nice, then, is that here we see that we can get more information about what has been performed, and we can also find the registry in Terraform, i.e. where we can find the configuration we can implement to check if this is being changed.
And what happens here is that if we go to one of these links, then we come straight to this ACL configuration.
We can now take out the security information that we get from the TFsec in addition, because it will explain what the problem is, what can be done to fix it.
And of course, we have to take a stance on the risk presented here, and is it something that is relevant to our infrastructure?
Because this is a very large set of security measures that should of course be taken into account if it is relevant to our infrastructure.
Here we see that we should set the limitations on who gets access to this Key Vault.
Then it comes in with a source example, i.e. Network, ACLs, Bypass, Azure Services, i.e. as long as it is an Azure service that tries, then it is fine, and then the default action is deny.
We already have a Key Vault, so we can take it with us now.
If we take this example with us, it goes to the Key Vault configuration, and we just scroll down since there was a lot here.
Here we have the Azure Key Vault, and we can put it there.
And if we now save it, then we can see without pushing anything, we can scroll down here, we can see that if we click save, then we click TFsec again.
Then we see here that we have one less on critical, and that would just say that we have removed, eliminated one of the security threats that exist for this infrastructure.
But this is something run on my machine, this is not deployed or implemented to the infrastructure that is Azure, and the test is just run on my machine.
Of course, there can be a lot of security challenges by going through, see what the security issue is, what the explanation is, how it can be fixed, on all of these down here.
But the thing is that we want to get this out to GitHub Actions and do a workflow, so that everyone who works with the same project gets the same tests,
and it is the same conditions for all the tests that are run, and that you have one place where you can possibly update and relate to these tests that are to be carried out.
So now I can quickly just take it away again, this one here, just like that.
And then we can choose to continue now in GitHub Actions, because here we see now that I have set up a YAML file under GitHub Workflows, which I call Terraform Security Check.
For example, I have put in here now that it should check if Terraform Validate is completed, and I have also put in a manual trigger, so that I can actually run it manually, just to test it while I'm doing it.
The thing is that you can put in, that you, for example, have some changes in repo or pushing or something like that, then you can check that Terraform Validate, for example, has passed, and then you can also put in that it will run new things afterwards.
Now we want to see here, here we have a security test, spin up Ubuntu Latest, and here we also have an environmental variable among other things, and then we run the steps, checkout, name, tfsec, aquasecurity, what we are going to do, working directory,
and GitHub Actions to make sure that we do not, and GitHub Token, which is there to prevent that we get a rate limit on the GitHub API when we run through all these checks.
We can quickly look at the market, just to see what we are actually running through here now.
Here we see, we have GitHub.com Marketplace, type Actions, here we look at tfsec, then we see that we get some suggestions, this one I have taken is tfsec-action, so if we go into it, then we will get an overview of what this does, how we configure it in our workflow,
and then we also have optional input, working directory, version, format, etc., etc., and here also GitHub Token, as we talked about, and then we can also choose to put the arguments we want, for example working directory, which I have put in.
So when we have done that, we can now look at our workflows in GitHub, go to GitHub.com, our repo, go into Actions, so here we see now that I have created this file already,
tfsec, and then I have a workflow dispatch event trigger, so that I can run it manually now, just to see that I get to run it here, but of course there can be other things that should be the check, that it has gone through,
that it can be, for example, finished with Validate, and that it is part of a larger workflow.
So if we just take a look at this one now, we akready know the outcome, but the thing is that we just want to check that this security check gives us a response,
so if we go back to all workflows, we see that the workflow has started, terraform security check, and then manually by me, and then we see here that we get a red cross on the security check,
status failure, and that would be that if we look at tfsec now, then we can see that it will be a very long list here, because it downloads a lot of different things to the runner when it is to run through.
Let's see, so if we press this one, we scroll all the way down to the bottom, this one is long, and then this one is complete.
So now we are back, here is a familiar display, which is the same as when we saw in VS Code, just that now we run it on a runner,
so an Ubuntu, which is spun up for this objective, run the test for us, and give us the answer back.
Here we see that we have two criticals, and the one critical is the one we remember; the ACL to this key vault of ours,
which made it not, or it thought it was very stupid that we had open access to the ACL from anywhere.
Here we see that the critical is part of our infrastructure as it is, so we should absolutely have taken notice of that.
But there are quite a few here that make this one fail, so we should of course only specify, for example, that low, no, we don't really need to do anything about that,
and medium may not even need to do anything about it, so we can set for example, that high and critical is what should trigger,
and not approve the infrastructure, but that this can be something we evaluate and look at, if there should be an evaluation.
So it's really just a simple news on how to create a workflow for the security check, and how we can look at Terraform configuration,
which is to solve these security challenges, and TFsec's explanation of what the security problem is, and why it is important to take a stance on it.