But what I want now is that when this pull request is carried out,
that my new code is merged with the main repo branch,
then I want something new to happen.
And that will be in this case, for example, that the infrastructure is to be deployed.
So therefore I now have a deploy infrastructure action workflow,
which I call deploy.yml.
And that would mean that I want that when something is pushed to the main branch,
then it will, and it is this folder, since I am now working in module 7,
I want it to be this folder, then I want something else to be done.
And that would be, for example, this deployment that we intend to carry out.
So then we can see here, okay, here are the steps I want to do.
Do a checkout, do a terraform init, do a plan, and do an apply.
So that when, for example, the pull request is carried out,
then the main branch will get the updated configurations.
Then this will be triggered to deploy.
So then we can say something okay, this one we have to push.
If we go back to actions, deploy infrastructure, then we can enable workflow.
And then we have to remember that if we now push something to the main from the local VS code,
then it will trigger the redeploy.
So it's not quite a good CICD practice, that it shouldn't be possible for me to push things to the main.
It should go through new branches, run through defined sets with tests,
and then pull requests to the main, which again triggers the deployment of the infrastructure.
And it's pretty straight forward workflow here.
This one is just going to deploy, because all of this code is going to be verified, checked, blah, blah, blah, blah.
This pull request should only be allowed to run through after it has gone through the defined tests.
In our case, it's just very simple, just because we're testing something.
And then we can go back to our GitHub.
Because now we remember that we can go back to Edit Network.
There is something I forgot to edit.
For example, think that source or destination port range should be something else, or the priority rule was something else.
So if, for example, you have seen that this priority rule should be 1,
the priority rule only has a number of follow-ups on how the rules are read in NSGEN.
The first that hits is valid, so it's important to think about a number of follow-ups on such things.
So let's save this one now in that branch, remember, it's in the Edit Network branch now.
And then we can say that we get source control pending, edit, ssh, priority.
So, we commit to that, and then we sync changes.
When we sync these changes, we remember that it should trigger a workflow.
So if we go to all workflows now, you will see here, edit, ssh, priority.
That workflow is checked, or it is started.
So then the validate job is started.
Check out, run Terraform init, and then run a Terraform validate afterwards, just to verify if it is approved.
Great, it's a success.
The job is a success, we can also see that in our VS Code.
No, not that one, let's see, GitHub actions.
Here we see that we have got validate number 11.
It is approved, where we have run Terraform validate, and it has passed through.
We did not get all the same info here as in Web GUI.
Here we get this information as well.
So if we then go to Validate, Workflows, then we also have the opportunity to see all workflows.
But what we wanted now, that was great, the validation is checked green.
We can also take a test later on where we actually do not get checked green.
But then we have verified that great, now the check is approved.
So if we then go to our pull request, then we can prepare a new pull request for which thing.
We can quickly just show it in GUI how it looks there.
Because if we then go to pull request, then we can see new pull request.
Then we can see compare changes, what compare changes, across branches, blah, blah, blah.
Here, base main, compare edit network, compare edit network with main.
And then we see here, that here we find that resources, NSG, or network security rule, SSH inbound,
is changed from priority from 100 to 101.
So then I can also create a pull request here in Web GUI, which is also quite nice and transparent.
But I can still use VS Code, since that is what I'm doing now.
Now we remember that our action, deploy infrastructure, is active,
so that it will then deploy, both remove it from the NSG rule.
Adn apply the new rule to it, because if I look at it,
then I will see something that should be here, because in the previous change,
there was nothing that was changed in the infrastructure.
It was just updated repo, because there was no workflow that triggered it.
Then there is SSH, and priority, and RDIN, so RDIN will be removed.
The priority on SSH will change now, after we run through it here.
So let's see, create a new pull request.
Let's see, here we have base main on edit network, edit SSH priority.
Let's run a create on that.
And then we will get a new pull request, and then we can see edit SSH priority.
It will then pop up as the option to take and merge pull request.
We will get the option to see what can be changed.
And then you can take a merge pull request,
and then it will run through by creating merge commit.
Then we can jump over to this interface, workflows.
Here we see, merge pull request is initialized, and that is under deploy infrastructure.
Because deploy infrastructure was the one that was supposed to start,
when something had been changed in the main file.
So if we just open it, something will happen.
And here it takes to run through checkout, terraform plan, terraform apply,
in relation to the workflow that we have set up.
So now we have set up the flow of it,
by using a branch, make changes.
Here we see, change priority 100 to 101.
That was what was supposed to be changed, and then RDP is destroyed.
If we run terraform apply, it will go through.
And then we have actually run through everything we thought of in this CICD workflow.
And that was actually just with validate,
so that we ran through that validates should be in the only test.
We are now going to see,
there is a security rule conflict,
tried to change the rule priority before it had deleted it.
Okay, that's kinda fine.
And then we see here, we got an error here now.
So this test was not,
there were actually two changes that were waiting for each other.
One was to delete the rule, and the other to change the rule.
So we got an error now,
that we tried to set the rule to the same priority as the other rule,
before they deleted the other rule.
So if we now then go and check,
how should we tackle this problem?
I can now double check just on NSG.
Here you can see that the rule has actually been deleted.
But of course it tried first to change it here to one.
So if I now just go to this one,
and then rerun,
I can choose to rerun only this one.
So, let's see.
I'll just rerun the job, because I'm just going to deploy it.
It doesn't matter.
We just try to implement the changes that have been made once again.
But here we see that now we just rerun the job,
and then its able to implement it,
because now there is no other rule that has that priority now.
And when the job is done,
then we can now see here that it's under Terraform apply,
get run through, and apply completed.
And here we see that I just need to ignore it.
One changes, and that's one of the NSG rules.
Here we see that if we take a refresh on the NSG rule,
then we see here that the priority is set to 101.
So then we have seen a bit of the process,
where we get a new branch, make changes,
run the tests, deploy, no, and make a pull request to main.
When there is a merging with main,
then the infrastructure is deployed to Azure
using a deploy workflow.
So here we can have many different workflows,
which are triggered by different things,
which makes it automatized.
A good start with a preliminary definition,
set with rules and tests that are run on the code,
infrastructure, and similar before it is deployed.
But this was just a test now with Validate,
where we saw that Validate checked,
and then of course there are a lot of things
we can set up to test in addition.
But this was just to test it,
and if you are now done with this infrastructure
and testing here, then of course you can just
go back to the terminal,
and then of course you can just run terraform-destroy
from the terminal here as well.
When I'm in the folder there,
I can just run terraform-init and terraform-destroy
to delete it here,
because I have it as long as I have
environmental variables in it,
or that I have connected them up with az-login.
So then I have run through the simple Validate test.
Then we will see how we can build on it a bit,
with some more tests here,
that one approved test,
run a new test,
run a new test, etc.
But when I'm done with using this
Edit Network branch,
I can press Command-Shift-P for Mac,
and then I get this up,
and then I can start writing
Git-colon and then Delete branch.
If I have Windows or Ctrl-Shift-P,
then I want to get the same menu up at the top there,
and then I can write Git-delete-branch.
We press it, and then we see,
no, I might not want to delete the main,
I can go to the main first.
So, go to the main,
press Command-Shift-P,
or Ctrl-Shift-P for Windows,
select Git-delete-branch,
select delete this one,
and then we will see that we have deleted
the branch that we used to edit the network.
So, we're done with that,
and then we can have as many other branches
to keep track of
when we're done with the editing we've done.