In this video, we will now begin to see how we can test our infrastructure,
so that it is certain that it meets the requirements we want it to meet
before it is deployed to Microsoft Azure in our context.
So the idea is that we can of course run some tests on the infrastructure
against our infrastructure via VS Code, as we use here,
before we eventually push it to the Git repository,
which is a trigger for a workflow that again goes through some different steps to get there.
But that's what the idea is here now, that we're going to get integrated tests
as part of this workflow, so that we, for example, now can run this infrastructure
through a number of tests in a different branch.
And when these tests are verified and eventually approved,
then we can run a pull request, that is, that we merge the branch that we have set up with main,
so that it becomes the relevant infrastructure for the infrastructure that is in Azure.
And there are some steps and some new things we are going to introduce now in this video,
and there are also some tools that we use, i.e. what we use to test it.
There are many different tools we can use to test our infrastructure,
so we can test the code, we can test the security of the code, etc.
But we take some that we are going through now,
and then of course we can also link to some different sites,
where we have several different tests that we can go through.
As you can see, there are a lot of reds that are screaming out in my VS code now,
and that's because I've installed something called Checkov.
Checkov is a tool that helps me, and so maybe a little in the strictest way,
for a demo test that we're going to do now,
because it is very much on what has to do with security, and that's good.
And then it comes with recommendations on what it is that it wants to do,
so that we can satisfy the potential security threats that are relevant.
But there are several tools, and there is one, as I said,
I have posted information on which tools I am testing now,
and the way we install them is in our own.
What we can start with, if we take Terraform validate,
so it is also a test that we can run.
We can integrate that Terraform validate is part of our test in GitHub Actions.
Because then you can see that if we run Terraform validate,
then you can check if the configuration is valid.
If it is not valid, then you will get a error message that this is not correct.
So if I, for example, on my main here,
this is a demo infrastructure that I have set up,
which I already run in Azure portal.
But then I have a slightly different approach here.
Here I only have different files that represent the different resources I have set up.
And then I have a main file where I have set up a resource group for all the resources here.
So you can take a look at that.
I have Provider, Main, Network, Storage Account, Variables and Key Vault,
which I use here now.
I have Terraform TF Wars and Secret TF Wars in addition to that.
So if I now, for example, have changed here that the resource group should be like this,
especially if something is written wrong,
if something is going to happen to the variable here,
so if I save it, then Terraform validate will now say that I use the name of a resource group
that is not declared from before.
So it will not get any names here.
And this can also be a simple test that we can implement in our GitHub Actions,
which then checks if this is approved to be deployed further.
So we can start with such a simple test as that we try to integrate Terraform validate,
and then we can then look further at different more advanced tests afterwards.
I just quickly change this back so that it is correct like that.
And then we can see here now that it validates,
because then it matches the way it is in our infrastructure now.
And then I just take Terraform plan out.
I can change Terraform plan because I have no changes.
I'm just going to show you that this is already running like this in Microsoft Azure
with some resources that are already created.
Infrastructure matches configuration, just go here.
RG Demo, here's Key Vault, NSG, Public IP, storage account, VM, disk,
NIC and the VM network to the machine.