Now we are getting pretty well prepared to take a look at the modules, but before we can start looking at that, we should take a quick look at the outputs.
Because it may be something when we start with the modules, that you have root modules and child modules, and possibly even more levels with child modules.
It may be that you want to send information between these modules, which means that if you expand a network or link one module, you will have information from what has been expanded in that module over in the root module.
We are not going to start with the module right now, but it's a bit tricky where we start first here.
But we can look at the output first, and then we can think about how we can reuse this later.
So what we are going to do is that we can create an output block, and then we can for example write here that it should be SAID.
And then we can think that if we then wish that after making this storage edge, then we wish to know the ID.
Of course, we cannot know the ID to this storage account before it has been created, so therefore we have to wait until this storage account has been created, until we can eventually find the ID.
And then we see here that I get a pretty good suggestion now from CoPilot, what I actually need.
And that's actually what it says here. I need value. What do I need of value?
Yes, I need Azurerm Storage Account, SADemo, which is the name of this one. So it's this resource's ID.
And if we take and write like this, then we see that we find a whole lot of attributes that we can actually list from or send to the output for a storage account.
But in our case now, we take an ID as an example. Where can I find the attributes I can use?
Yes, if we go to Terraform or registry.terraform.io, and then we go into Azure Documentation, then we can here write storage account, scroll down to storage.
And then if we then search for attribute references, then we see here that we have all the things we can add on the backend to find that type of information when we run to an output.
So here we had ID, and it could be, for example, if we run a network, then maybe we want to give that network IP range or something like that.
And that's especially if you, for example, are going to set network rules on that network, then you would have the need to know the ID of that network.
So that was actually what we needed to do now to get an output, but you have to check that it works.
What is important to think about now is that a value on the output will not be shown in the beginning of the plan, because the resource does not exist when we run the plan.
Therefore, we have to run the whole round with plan and apply.
We run Terraform init, so we run Terraform plan -out main.tfplan. When the plan is ready, we run Terraform apply "main.tfplan"
Changes to outputs: said, known after apply, plan two, two that are added, and then we can start to see here that the storage account and the resource group is what is being set up.
And when we have run apply, then we see here that we have apply completed, resources 2 added, outputs, here we have said, and this is the whole ID that represents the storage account that we have just set up.
Now we can go into the portal to see that our resource has been set up.
Under resource groups, we can see here now, rgdemo001, satimdemo7643 If we click on that, we will then be able to find out.
If we, for example, click on JSON view here, we see that we have the ID of the storage account, which is the same as we got the output.
And then it's like that, if we were to have done anything more with the storage account there now, in Terraform, then we could have sent this output and used this in another context.
If we were to have set up, configured, or done anything with this resource, then we can refer to this ID, so that we have been able to continue.
Yes, if this resource has been set up in another module, then we can send this ID over to the root module, if we were to do anything more with this resource itself.
That was actually what I was going to go through with you in connection with the output.
Because then we can see here now, if we just enter one module 3, but maybe now in the next module 4, we will start to have one top root module with several sub-modules.
That is to say a collection with Terraform files that makes up one configuration, a set of resources, etc.
But as always, Terraform destroy at the end, and then we can see that we take out that one, confirm that we want it.
And finally, we see now that the resource group and the resource group are deleted, and then we don't have to worry about something that will cost us in Azure.