Now we are very well prepared to take on modules, but because we can start to buy them, we start to take a cart in your output.
Because it is possible to have modules with modules, such as road modules, child modules, and even if you are at a higher level with child modules.
It is possible to be able to use them and see information.
It is a module that allows you to do a training course, if you are going to talk about a network or a connected one module,
then you want to have more information, because it is also possible to talk about a module over it.
Maybe road modules.
We start with a module, maybe a few, but it is a bit like this.
We start first.
But we can start to buy the first output, and then we can think about the cost.
Now we can use this scene.
So what we are going to do is that we can create a output block, and then we can, for example, write here that it is going to be s-a-ide.
And then we can think that if we want to get a large account, then we will get a bit of ID.
We can now get a bit of ID, and then we have to get a bit of ID.
So therefore we have to get a bit of ID here, and then we have to get a bit of ID.
And then we have to get a bit of ID to get a bit of ID.
From the copy-election, we have to get a bit of ID.
And that is also possible to get a bit of ID.
I want to get a value, I want a value, I want a value, I want a value, I want a s-a-dm storage account,
a s-a-dm, which is a name on this one.
So this is the s-a-dm, and we have to get a bit of ID.
Now we can start writing this as we see that we have a whole deal with ask for an answer
which we actually read, especially since we are sent out But everything is still on our account.
But have to get a large account, and then we have to get an ID I-a-dm.
That's right, now we have to object to pick something a new thing like
If we have to run on Terraform and RAID subway TerraformIo, then we have to get a BEST in Transure documentation.
So now we have to write storage accounts.
I'm going to write a story, and then we'll search for a review of the references.
So let's say here that we have all the things that we can do on the back,
to find the information that we're going to do on the outside.
So here was the idea, and that could be, for example, if you're going to talk about the network,
then you might be able to go into the network, like,
e-prange, or something like that, and that's very special, for example,
if you're going to talk about the network, then you're going to have to go into the network.
So that was actually what we had planned to do now,
to get an output, but now we have to check that it works.
That's what's important to think about now, that it's a value on output.
We don't want to come and show it to the audience, because it's that the resources don't exist,
when we do the plan.
Therefore, I think that we have to do the whole run with the plan and apply.
So let's do it for a minute.
So let's do it for the plan out.
Not for the plan.
When the plan is done, let's do it for the plan.
No, no.
Change, change the output.
Assault ID, no one after the plan.
Plan two, two that are dead.
And then we can see here that it's not...
Start check and resource group.
That's what will be applied.
So that's the plan.
So let's see if the story is over.
And maybe we have a lot of work to do.
Oh, no, we have heard for the apply.
So let's see here that we have completed resources to edit outputs.
Assault ID, and this is the entire ID that is represented.
Start check out.
So we have to do it.
We can go into the plan, but let's see if the resource has to do it.
Any resource groups, let's see here.
I'll give it a name.
Assault Team Demo 2643.
And I'll give it a name.
Find out.
For example, I'll give it a name.
Jason, I'll give it a name.
So that we have a large account,
which is the same one we got.
And now that we've got the name,
with the large account,
in the third form,
we can see the output,
and use the name in an A in the same name.
And if we have to configure the output,
or with the name, this resource,
we can refer this name,
because we have to set it up.
And if this resource has been represented
with an A in the module,
we can see this in the Over-Test.
It's a road module,
but we'll do it more with this resource.
That's what I'm thinking about.
I'll give it a name.
Map is a module 3,
but maybe the next module 4,
we'll have a top road module
with several smaller modules.
I just want to say a summary
of the four modules,
with a configuration,
set it up with the resource line in the same name.
But as always, the third form,
destroy, and then we can see
that we've done it.
We've got the name,
and then we've got the resource group,
and the resource group,
and then we're going to use the name,
Erscher.