In this video, we're going to see how we can use more complex variable types.
And then we'll start by going to our variables file.
Here we have all the variables that we've worked with in module 3.
And then I can now type in variables, and then I'll type in, for example, just here.
AZ_regions, for example.
And then I can now take and do.
Here you can see that my co-pilot is actually coming up with a pretty good suggestion.
I can let it be for now, so we can go through it manually.
For that, we have to write type, and then we have to write that we have to define what type of variable it is.
And that will be a list.
In addition, we also have to put in parentheses what the content in this list should be for now.
Because it can only be one type of content in this one that we remember from the other variables.
So we define, we have actually just defined string all the way here.
But if we want a list, it can be string, it can be bool, or it can be number.
So if we then take string in this case, then we can take description.
And then we can write Azure regions for resources.
And then we can have default value.
And then we see here that the value comes up with brackets aroudn itself.
And then we also have to, of course, since this is strings, have quotes around it.
So if we then, let's see, I think we need, depending on you.
So if we then just write North Europe.
So West, like that.
Let's see, maybe it has West US.
Yes, we don't need to have something more since we have taken what we need.
And what we can see now is that we have defined a list.
This can be seen as an array or something like that, if you are familiar with it from before,
another scripting or programming.
And then it would say that the content that is here, it always starts at zero.
And the content here is what becomes number one, and then two and three, of course.
So let's see how we can use it, so that we specify which one we want to have.
So if we then take, I can take West Europe here.
And since I've just used it most before.
So, remember to save it.
So the way I use it here, it would be when I go to my main.tf.
And then we can say here, we already have var location.
But I'm just going to show you how we can use it in the resource group.
Because then it will be var, and then it will be azregion.
And then we see here that we can fill in with, for example, specify zero.
When we say zero, it will be the first in this list, which will then be West Europe in our case.
And we can see that if we go here.
If we then just save it in, run terraform init.
We drag it a little further up, and then run terraform console;
var.azregions[0], so we just have azregions.
No, let's see.
So, now we see that if we define it like that, we see that we have different output on it.
So when we then put it here, it will then get the information from the list itself.
And that way we can use the content list, or a variable with a type of list.
If we were to have another type of content here, we had to define, for example, that it should be boolean.
Because we could not have had that this would have been like that, North Europe, and false.
This is not a legal value for the list, where we have to define that it has one type of content.
So then we can just check, if we exit out of the console, take like that, terraform plan.
But we can still take the version like that.
Then we write there, because now North Europe will be set instead of West Europe.
Then we take terraform fmt, to get better readability.
And then we take terraform plan -out=main.tfplan.
When the plan is done, we can just see here that we have received that the storage account will be set in North Europe.
And then we have seen that we can pick up that information from a list.
That was actually what I was going to go through with the list type.