In this video, we're going to look at a new type.
We're going to look at Variables Maps.
As we said, we're going to write variables again.
We're going to write, for example,
a nice use case for using Maps.
For example, VM size.
Where you can have mapping between
what the name of the VM is,
and what it is in, for example, Azure.
If we look at Azure's VM name,
i.e. Sizes, or Stock Keeping Unit, as it was called,
we can easily make a mapping between
what type of VM we want to use.
We haven't used a VM with Terraform yet,
but I can just show you an example of it,
but you can also see if we find a good use case here.
Because this is standard B2S.
It will be difficult to remember,
so if we know that in a configuration, or in a setup,
we're just going to have a type of VM,
we can, for example, do something like this.
We type, type equals map,
and then we write a string.
No, we don't need to have that one there.
And then we write default, like this.
We can just do that.
And then we can see that if, for example,
we set up the VM there, it should be this version.
If we set up the VM there, it should be this version.
In a way, we can check what this type of info is,
and then based on that, this VM size will be selected.
We can also, for example, have written that it has been small,
medium, and then we add large, like that.
And then we have simply now been able to specify that,
ok, variable VM size,
and also said, for example, ok, should it be small, medium, or large,
then it would have been the VM,
the stock shipping unit of the VM we have received when we deployed it.
So then we can easily see here,
the shipping unit looks like we are sure of the format.
We can write var.vm-size.small.
Then we see here that we get,
the content will then be standard,
MB1S, medium, large.
Then we see that there is a key pair,
so we have one value that is mapped to another value,
and then we let go of the relationship to the names,
which, for example, is a bit complex,
or a bit difficult to remember in the past, which is such a setup.
So then we can, for example, if we are going to set up a test environment,
then we can say, ok, should it be small, or something like that,
then it is mapped directly to how much VM size we get.
So then we have looked at maps,
how we can, we can also specify
whether it should be string or number on maps in addition.
So then we have looked at both lists,
we have looked at maps, and we have looked at locals,
and we have looked at regular variables,
so then we are starting to get a pretty good basis for our further work,
where we are going to start building a little more complex infrastructure,
and use modules.