In this video, we're going to see how we can connect to our Azure tenant using Azure Seal Eye.
Now we have access to the portal.
We have made sure that our users have enough rights in the portal.
We have set up an app registration or a service principle.
We have given our service principle enough rights.
So the last thing we do now is to make sure that we can actually connect to our tenant using Azure Seal Eye.
We have continued to work with Azure Service Principle using Azure Seal Eye.
So if we click on view file more, we can see to sign in with the service principle in the app in the tenant to the password.
And that is the information we have now after we have set up our service principle.
And then we can either go and copy and paste.
Then we can go to Visual Studio Code.
And here I have just pasted again.
Here I have some of my information in color text.
I'm going to remove this so it's not any sensitive information anyway.
I have the display name and the rename, but I'm not going to use it anyway either.
So what I have to do now is that I have to have an app in mine.
We have to paste it in there.
Then we have to have the secret, then we have to have it in there.
And then we have to have the tenant in ours.
We have to have it in there.
So then when we have everything we need, we have the command we need.
We specify how we are going to log in.
We have the username, we have the password, we have the tenant we are going to use.
Then we can just run this command.
Just right-click and choose Run Line in Terminal.
Let's see.
So, it was just that I was wrong.
Then we see that we have logged in.
Now we are connected to the tenant in it.
Then we do a quick check to confirm that we are actually logged in to the tenant.
It is that we can go back to this documentation for Azure CLI.
You can find the different commands you can use.
For example, EC account manager, Azure subscription information.
Then we can click on the different ones if we want to go into the different commandlets.
To see how they are going to be used.
One thing that can happen is, for example, the resource groups as a main on this tenant.
So we can just search for group.
EC group, we see here.
Manage resource group, then template deployments.
We click on that.
Then we can see over here how the commandlets we have.
Here we have, for example, EC group list.
Then we see that list resource groups.
If we just take that one.
Back to VS Code and paste it.
Then we see that it is going to list out the resource groups you have in the tenant.
We see here that the format is that you have both the subscription, the height of the subscription, the resource group and where it is located.
What location it is in.
But if you, for example, only want to know the names.
Then you can write, for example, EC group list dash table.
Then we see here that we list out the resource groups in a more readable form.
Instead of getting it in such a JSON format.
And if you see here now, you see that we have the resource group that was set up in conjunction with the fact that we needed a resource group.
To be able to operate a storage account that was necessary to run the cloud shell we used to operate the service principle.
So then we see here that we have this available.
We can also, for example, go into the tenant via Azure portal.
So we open Azure portal.
Then we see here, tenant 01.
Then we go to resource groups.
We use there.
Then we see here that we also have a list and a list of which resource groups are in this tenant.
And then we see that we have some connected tenants in the portal.
We are also connected to the VS code.
And then we have done everything together so that we can begin to deploy resources.