In this video, we're going to set up a service principle, or an app registration,
which allows us to connect to our internet via Visual Studio Code,
which we use to push or to set up our infrastructure using Terraform later in this class.
To do this, you can see here, we go to the documentation for Microsoft,
which is in Work with Azure Service Principle using the Azure CLI.
Azure CLI is a command line network that makes it possible for us to communicate with Azure,
and we can do that via Web GUI when we're going to set up this service principle.
So if we now click on the link Create Service Principle,
we see here that when you create a service principle, and use this command line,
it will output credentials that are in plain text, which we have to take care of.
This is important, we have to take care of it, because it will show up at some point,
so we don't have to set up a new secret password later to log in.
If you're a little unsure about what a service principle or an app registration is,
it says a little bit about what it is about here.
You can read it if you want.
Here it just quickly goes through how we set it up, so that we can see and connect
to our Azure tenant with Visual Studio Code.
What we do is that it takes with us this command here,
for this, Create a Service Principle with the required parameters.
Then we see here that MySubscriptionID is the one we're going to have with us,
to be able to choose where we're going to have the rights with the service principle that we set up.
I just copy it in, and then I go here.
Here we see that we have something called, up at the top there,
we have a command line limit.
What we see is, welcome to Azure Cloud Shell.
We now just press bash, and then I choose that I must have a storage account,
because there are some files that are going to be set up,
so then I just choose Create Storage Account.
We don't need to think so much about it now.
Now we go through what we need to get it in place,
so that we can get started.
A storage account comes back to what it is,
but as the name suggests, it's a place where we can and need it.
This can take a while, but when it comes and is set up,
we get a command prompt that we can use.
When the Cloud Shell is ready to use,
we're going to paste in this command of ours,
and then we're going to hack the subscription ID,
because that's what we see that we need.
Now I have MySubscriptionID,
and then we have it available in our tenant.
And then it looks like this.
Now the Cloud Shell is ready.
I can just paste in my command.
In addition, I have to go to Subscription,
because I need this ID now,
so I just take it with me with it,
and then I choose to paste it in.
And when I press Enter now,
I will ... Sorry, we have to have Roll, of course.
Roll, and that should then be Contributor.
Contributor means that you have the ability
to remove or add new rights,
but you have to have full Contributor,
that is, contribute to the subscription ID that gives it.
So you can update and delete all kinds of resources in there,
but you can't remove resources,
no, access for others with Contributor.
So, we just press Enter on it,
a little script file on it.
Like that.
Then I think it will work much better.
And there we see that now the service principle is updated,
and then we see here that we get our App ID,
we get the display name,
we also get the password or the secret,
and this is the one we have to take care of.
So now it is important that the one who updates this service principle
takes care of this information.
I like to store it in a place where you don't
share and have all the information,
for example, the alternate ID,
or sometimes you don't need to have stored together
with the App ID and password,
because that's what usually connects to the tenant.
If you use a password manager,
please put it in there,
because then you can see here now that I need to take
this information with me,
because it will not be available to me.
Later, when I close this window,
then we can see that this one has a display name,
then this is the display name,
I can show you right here that we have a commandlet
that makes it possible to set a name
so that we do not get a random name,
but if we go to Azure Active Directory,
then we scroll down to App Registrations,
All App Applications,
then we see here that now it has Azure CLI
with today's data and so on.
If I click on this one,
then I can, for example,
choose to change the name,
for example, to App Tim,
just like that,
to make it so that the initials
show that it is mine,
because you want to share this tenant with several,
so it's stupid if you have a lot of different names,
and now it shows that now I have an App Tim
that is mine,
and then there would like to be more down there,
because students can share the tenant with you.
If you want to set this up in the same line,
then you can see that under the command that is run now,
then we have a service principal,
where we can specify both the names
on our service principal,
how the role it should have,
and the scope.
Here you can see that the example in this one
shows a resource group,
but we can still just stop the subscription in it,
so if we just take this,
write a name as we want,
write that it should be contributor,
and then we take subscription and subscription ID,
then we get all the information at once,
so we let go,
and think that we have to rename it in the portal.
But again, now we have set up our service principal,
we need to take care of this,
because then we will see how to connect us up
with SLCLI via VS Code later.