When you have been invited into a group in Blackboard, and I have invited you into a tenant, you will receive an e-mail.
It may seem that you will get some warning that this e-mail looks a bit weird, but it is at least a legitimate e-mail that invites you into a tenant,
where we will carry out the practical tasks in this field.
And you can't recognize it, both on the tenant name, it's probably written 01 for your invitation, it will depend on which group you are in and who you are invited to join with.
And then you will see the domain name here.
When you get this e-mail, you can just choose to accept the invitation, that is, we have to accept this invitation.
And it is then on your NTNU user, so that you do not use the same login as with regular federal users.
So then you just press accept invite.
And when you press accept invite, it will go on to get a message that now I can choose which user I want to join with.
I will now show that I have tested to invite my e-mail user.
For you, it will stand for your NTNU student address, so that you can log in with me.
And since I now have two trillions of authentications on this user, I would like to get a message that I need to get a warning that I am helping to log in on this user.
If you do not have two trillions of authentications, I think it will go very straight forward, but most NTNU users now have two trillions of authentications.
I just choose to continue, and then I would like to see now that I log in on this account, and I would like to see that I get a warning, or that I get a warning from NTNU.
Multiple file data collection is just a good thing, because you just have to be in this NTNU.
When we have logged in, I see that I have logged in with several users since this is now for a test, so you will just have to choose your NTNU student.
The first thing that is important to check when you log in to your tenant is that it actually stands in the correct tenant.
Many of you have access to NTNU's default tenant, and you can check that by going up to the right here, and then we press switch directory.
If we first press the name switch directory, we see here that it is now in default directory.
This one I would not be able to have the opportunity to do the operations or tasks that we are going to do in the infrastructure as a code.
Because the NTNU tenant is of course only for NTNU and Damage, we are going to have our own little plaything where we do not affect anyone else.
So if I now press switch, I will then switch to that tenant, it may already be in it when you go in, but in my case it is something that is not in it.
And then I want to see to the left that it is now in the tenant that I have been invited into, tenant 01.
It is important to check if you want to go in and that it actually stands in that tenant.
And then you can also go in to Azure Active Directory. We have to make sure that we have the right details we need in this tenant.
Then we go to properties, or first of course on Azure Active Directory, scroll down to properties, and scroll all the way down to access management for Azure resources.
Here we choose yes, that this one should be able to manage all Azure subscriptions and management, choose directly save.
Now the user that I have been invited into this tenant has got the necessary rights or has all the rights.
Note that you are students who share the same tenant, so someone has to be a little careful what you actually do, but we are going to do everything together via Terraform.
This is a lot to be able to look into and develop the service principle, or the app registration that we are going to look at later, to get the opportunity to authenticate and stand against the tenant we are using with VS Code or Azure CLI.
So now we have the necessary rights in place, and if we go back to home, then we can go to the top, and then we can write subscription.
And when we have the subscription, then we see here that the subscription ID is yours, we will come back to it, because we need it in the next operation when we are going to develop the service principle.