In this video, we are going to deploy a static web page to Azure using Terraform.
The reason we do that is that in the previous video, we have also looked at workspaces and so on.
And then we may need a resource where we also want to see different versions of this resource based on which workspace we are in and how we deploy it.
What I will only go through in this video is the deployment of the static web page itself, so that it becomes a relevant exercise.
How can you adapt this configuration to work with workspaces and deploy it so that you see that, for example, this is the development web page, and this is the production web page, with different resources in Azure.
So what I have here, web demo, main.tf, providers.tf, terraform.tf-vars, variables, providers first, our backend, which we have previously configured as a state file.
The key must be specified for the project we are working with. Here I just have a web demo. You can see that this file is displayed in the storage page.
Add main, we go here, random string again, because we need it in the storage account.
A resource group, rgweb, var, rgname, location, var location, variable location, name of the storage account.
Here we remember that we must have a unique name, so we take the variable as a name and put it together with a random string.
The resource group is rgweb, location, rgweb, account tier, standard, account replication type, lrs, local redundant storage.
Under the Azure storage account, we add a new block called static website.
That means that we specify the index document that will be on the static webpage, because the static webpage is a field or a function that we can add and add to the storage account.
The index document, var index document, the reason I use variables here is because I use several places.
Here add an index.html file to the storage account, and then we see resource, resource.rm, storage blob, index.html, we create var index document, the same as before.
Where is this place going to be? The storage account name is sa_web.name, storage account web, storage container name, create a $web that represents.
It has a written description if you go to the storage account, look at $web, storage container name, it has a special function, which means to add static web pages.
Type block, content type, text.html, and then source content, i.e. what is included in this html page that we create.
Finally, we take an output. What are we outputting? Yes, we output the storage account's primary web endpoint.
That means that a storage account has a primary web endpoint, and that is the html index html file we create, that we add here, we will then get output on it.
We have declared the variables, location, rgname, saname, source content, index document.
Below tfvars, we have West Europe, rgweb, saweb, here we see html, web page created with terraform, the end h1, i.e. title h1, and this is source content.
So this content is then added to the index document, which is index.html file.
Back to the main, I have to make sure that I am in the right folder, web demo, terraform, init, and when it is done, terraform, plan, so out main.tf.plan.
Sorry, wrong on var, forgot to save, so then it is saved, run it again, when the plan is run, we run for to add output, primary web endpoint, known after apply.
Now we see that it is the resources that we have declared in the main that will be created.
We just run terraform, apply, so we will see that the resource comes up in Azure.
So, apply completed, notice that here the primary web endpoint comes out at once, but it takes a little time before it is actually up and running, as to give it a little time before it is available.
But before I open it, I have to push the last code over to my repo, web demo, terraform, commit, and then I sync it out to github repo, so that I have the file there and not just locally.
Then I can go back to my demo github repository, here I see now that web demo, two minutes, I see here that my configuration file is in.
It will be a little back and forth between different repositories, because I have several repositories where I test and run my different configurations and modes, so that I can put the code in the github terraform repository in addition, so that it becomes available in it.
When that is done, we take a look, maybe when we open the URL, open web page created in terraform, perfect.
Then we get our resource, a html page, and it contains the web page created in terraform with header 1.
If we go to the resource group in the portal, search rgweb, we see here that it includes the storage account, and then on the left side, if we scroll down to the storage account, we find a static web page, and below static web page, we get the primary endpoint.
Here we also see index.document.name, index.html, which is the file we have created, and Azure Storage Container has been created to host your static website, and that is $web container, which is what represents the static app.
So if I now go back to my code, I can now see that if I go to the tfvars, new, save, run a new terraform plan, we will see that I get a confirmation that it will be replaced, that is, the variable source content will be replaced with this one.
So if I now run one like that, it's done, then the content has been replaced, look, there we see, now we have got new.
And this was actually just a quick example of a static web page we use terraform to deploy, we will use the two videos that we have gone through in this part now to make a fun and exciting task.