In this video, we are going to look at the use of environmental variables.
We find under registry, terraform, IO providers, etc. etc. under RRM.
The reason we want to use environmental variables is because we might let go of the option for sensitive information to come in clear text.
We will run a VC login, for example, because terraform has the necessary information through client ID, security, tenant ID, subscription ID in the environmental variable available.
Then it understands and knows where it should perform the handling.
So if you look here, the way we use this value is that we are of course status 01 here with the input we have available.
It will then be client ID, security, tenant ID and subscription ID.
All of this is known to us, we have already used it via VC login, but we can now simply paste it in instead of in the terminal.
Once you use environmental variables like this, the variable is short-lived.
So if I paste it in and have thought, as I said, paste in all of this, which was the value for this.
So when I paste in and press enter now, and of course have the correct information, which is after for my user.
Then it will be gone when I close the terminal window here, so no one can use it afterwards if I paste it in.
So it is stored for this session and only this session.
The next time I open it, I have to paste it in.
I also recommend that you store the information here in your own private key vault or encrypted information that you do not get access to here.
Of course, we are only dealing with a demo environment, but in a real world scenario, this would be the information that has been stored and secured.
So if I now press enter on this, I will put this as the variable, and then I can afterwards list out and see how the information that is in these variables.
So what I do, if I paste it in and put it here, now it's just this one.
But if I paste it in, and then I write in, it's a bit different from the operating system, but then I see here now that I have the subscription client secret identity, which is in my environmental variables.
And that would just say that if I, for example, now have been and is in the back-end folder and run Terraform init and Terraform plan and apply, then I have used the information that has been stored here.
Of course, I would not want anything that is valid and functional here, but of course you have to enter your information.
And what I have to think about now, if I now press to just close this terminal, and then I take up a new one, then we can see that if I write in now, I do not have these environmental variables available anymore, because it is a new session.
So that for each time I put it in here, and then I write in, then I see that I have them available at the bottom and can then just start rolling out the infrastructure via Terraform without having to do ac login and so on.
And this is the same information that we put into GitHub, which is the variables that we can use when we want to run GitHub Actions alone.