In this video, we will get started with getting GitHub in place.
We will ensure that we get the necessary information so that GitHub can be authenticated against our tenant.
I will now install a new repository, because this is the aim; for showing and demonstrating.
I have now logged in to GitHub, and you can create your own user on GitHub, and is now under my repositories.
I will choose here and create a new repository.
I can now call it github-terraform, choose public and read me, I can now choose a terraform, ignore file, git ignore file.
So we can add files that will be ignored to be synced to the GitHub repository, because there are files that we do not want.
To bring to the GitHub repository, choose create, when the GitHub repository is created, you can now choose under code there.
So we see here that we can choose HTTPS, SSH or GitHub CLI, I can now choose the HTTPS.
Copy it, I take it with me to VS Code, clone GitHub repository, paste it in the urn at the top there.
Press enter, clone, clone from url, choose where we want to put it.
Yes, when you open the folder, you see here that there is my gitignore file, here I can add a type of file that I do not want to push over to, or transfer data to GitHub repo,
because there can be sensitive information that I do not want to be available in a repository.
In addition, we have a readme file, where we can begin to enter what kind of information we want to be.
We can now first start by saying that what we need to do is that we have to create a backend,
that is, we want terraform state file to be created when we plan to apply to our infrastructure.
There is a state file that contains sensitive information, and we do not want it to be included in GitHub.
State file is what should be mirrored in the infrastructure, as is in Microsoft Azure for our part, in a configuration file.
And we want to have a secure storage of those files, they should be stored and encrypted,
and we want them to be checked in and checked out when it is accessed by someone who is performing apply and plan against this infrastructure.
So one way we can do that in the beginning is not manually go into the portal,
set up a storage account, a storage container, and add that container as a storage place for the backend, or for the terraform state file.
Or we can also do this using terraform, so we can first try to do it using terraform, and then we'll see how it goes.
But first we need to add the secrets that we need to have in GitHub to be able to connect to VSCode.
Under settings in the top-end of the repository, we can find out where we can add secrets.
That's because we're going to have secrets that will create safe and secure way to can connect to our Azure Tenant,
because we're not going to store anything in plain text, we're going to make sure everything is encrypted.
And then we also need to store secrets as a hidden variable that is not possible to read later, we can just change it.
And under actions we can choose a new repository secret.
Here we have a fixed naming that is set for how we name our Azure secrets or Azure information.
So to add the secret, I can enter a name, and I can follow a typical standard like this.
I can add Azure Client ID, Azure Client Secret, Azure Tenant ID, and Azure Subscription ID.
I can also add an Azure Credential, and then I'll add all the JSON information that comes out when I've set up the service principle
using Azure CLI Web Cloud Shell when I'm starting.
But if you don't have this information from before, you can also just copy it here, and then you can fill in the Client ID,
and then you can add the secret, the subscription ID, and the Tent ID where it should be.
So I'm going to update all of these, so what I basically do is that I take Client ID,
and I paste in my Client ID in this field, and I press Add Secret.
When I press Add Secret, I won't be able see this information again, I can just update it with new information.
I'll do something for all of them.
And when I've done that, we see here that we have Client ID, Client Secret, Credentials,
Subscription ID, and Tenant ID.
The Credentials also contain all of the JSON format of all the information that is there.
It's just to have everything together if we need to use it one time.
So then we've actually got our GitHub repository, so we've put together the secrets we need,
and then we can continue with this repository.