Okay, now we have our backend in place. We have the GitHub repository in place.
We have also put in the necessary secrets in GitHub, so that we can use the GitHub Actions now
and initiate something that will happen using GitHub Actions.
What we have to watch out for now, or what is a good policy to keep in mind
is that so far we have just been working with files locally on my machine.
Some of you have probably used GitHub or GitLab or similar repository themselves.
But now I have prepared my own GitHub Terraform repository, which I use for this purpose.
And that is just to show that we should use a repository that makes it possible for more people to access the same repository.
Because there are often many who work with the same project, but dont normally sit alone and work with projects.
And then we see here in the file here now, for example, if I go into the main, and then I just change, for example, from grs-lrs and save it,
then it will eventually bring up a number on source control.
Then we can see here that if I just say ssa-lrs-local-with-a-storage commit,
then I can then choose sync and changes, then it will synchronize it out to GitHub.
If you have not authenticated yourself against GitHub, you will get prompted with opening your browser and authenticate yourself against GitHub.
So if I now go to GitHub, then I can now just see a refresh.
On that page, I will see here that now it says the last commit, or the last push, commit from me, ssa-lrs-local-with-a-storage,
and just change the backend, because I'm going to change it back to grs now, just to show.
Then we have our backend folder, now in GitHub, with the main, tf-plan, and variables.
This is, of course, just the one we have made, in relation to the deployment of the backend.
But now we see that there are much fewer folders here, and files here, than there actually are in this GitHub-terraform folder on my local machine,
where we have a .terraform with providers, etc., etc.
And that would be the file that we do not want to push over to the repository in GitHub,
because then it's this one, because here you have some big files in here, and tf-vars, you can enter sensitive information,
which then takes it away, in addition to taking away a few other things that we do not want to have,
which we see in the Git-ignore file.
So, when that is said, we can now move on and start with what should be the theme for this passage here,
and that is then workspaces.
Workspaces is something that we should and can be familiar with, at least with the use of Terraform,
and not least with the use of GitHub and GitHub Actions that are coming,
because it is what we have mentioned many times, that we must have different environments for the different resources that are deployed.
It could be that we have a developer dev, and we have staging, and we have a production environment.
And then we want to have different environments that we can work towards,
and that is a completely necessary approach, since you can't just do something and push it or deploy it to production without knowing that it actually works.
In developer HersheyCorp, it says a lot about workspaces, how it works.
Workspaces is one approach you can take to use different environments.
By using Terraform, there are several approaches that can be, including HersheyCorp Cloud or Terraform Cloud.
It can also be that you want to divide it up into separate folders and so on,
and there is a lot of this that is known from typical IAC terminology or best practices and so on,
and there is no one that is better or worse than the other, but it is more that you have to adapt it to your needs,
because it is often both the complexity of the size of the team and etc. that work with these projects,
which is a bit dependent on which solution you go for.
Some can choose an approach that suggests that you clone the map and have a folder structure,
while others go for a workspaces approach.
So now we're going to build a little further and use workspaces with Terraform in VS Code.
So what we're just going to do really easy here is to show that we can use workspaces.
We can start by building a new folder, not under back-end, but under GitHub Terraform,
and then we can now just remove the back-end, or whatever we would like to have with what is here,
because we can now use the same back-end for what is done.
So if we just took it fast forward a little, we did it like this.
This is known information.
If you have built a Terraform, you have built a main.tf, provider.tf, Terraform.tf.vars and variables.
The reason I built providers in addition now is to show that we can also divide it into even more divided pieces,
so that we can get a more transparent structure on our infrastructure,
so that if we were to integrate the main, for example, we have so far only used a few providers,
but it can also be good to take out the main and have your own provider.tf,
because there can be a lot of providers that we use, and then it gets a little confusing to have it in the main,
and then we can just have the resources in the main instead of the variables, or the modules that we picked up.
What is important when we look at the providers here now, I just copied the one from our back-end,
so we can not use the same Terraform state file key, because then we would try to overwrite it,
and then we would say, hey, I deleted everything from my back-end, and it would be a bit of a crisis,
so it's okay to use here now, that we can remove just that one,
and then it could have been identified as a whatever application or similar,
if you want this to be, but I can just get something, since I thought I was going to use
a very simple one-off of WorkSpaces, using and creating resource groups.
Of course, you can add on as many resources, but I will show you how to create a resource,
where you can use this type of information to do it with Dev, Staging, etc.
So now I have the providers, so if I then make sure that I am in the correct folders,
when I run Terraform ls, here I have now all the files I need,
and then I can write Terraform init, in order to see that it gets the provider,
and everything works as it should with it.
It is good, and then we must of course develop what we are going to do.
It is very simple, resource, Azure RM, and then it is resource group,
we just write RG name, and then we take the location for the resource group,
we create the variable RG name, and then we create the variable RG location,
and then we have to remember that we must have them in the variables declaration,
so we say then write variable as string as, so we save it,
and then we go back to main again, because then we have taken it in,
and then the idea was that what was going to happen now,
if I deploy this resource group here, then it would get what is, for example,
set as value inside of here, and inside of there, and then we take the demo,
and then I would have gotten, if I were to deploy only the resource group there,
then if I have run in here, and then we take Terraform,
no, it has been run, Terraform plan out main tfplan,
and then of course forget the provider, and feature again, Terraform,
init, initialize the backend, the backend is done, we see here that now,
although it is a new file, a new file has been made here, we can now quickly see in the resource group
now, for backend TFState, that there has actually come a new file in this storage container,
that contains these files for the TFState file for our backend,
if we go to the storage container, then we will see that we have got a file,
which is called RG Terraform TFState, and it represents the infrastructure for Terraform
in VS Code, we can check here, that there is nothing, it's just a resource group,
which is going to be deployed, then we can start with main, then we take the resource group here,
and then we have Terraform plan out main to after plan, and then we will see, now if I run
this resource group here now, then we understand that it gets the name, which is defined in the variable
it is pretty straight forward, but if I now want to have more environment to work with,
that I do not want this to be always out, because if I take Terraform workspaces list,
then we see here that it is now in default workspace, if I create a, let's see, Terraform
workspaces, new dev, and then we can write, just write that, and then we can then write
eventually test, or we can write prod, so if we then take and list out these again,
then we will see now that we have got three new workspaces, we have dev, prod and stage in
workspaces list, and then if we take Terraform, workspaces, select, dev, then we will now see that we
have switched to workspaces dev, and that is also how I want it, because now I use the same code repo
for all my projects, so I don't have to copy or think that it does not sync with making an
changes in dev or something like that, now I use one of the same repo, but I have different workspaces
instead, and that is fine, but if I now take and run and deploy here with dev, then the resource group still
be the same, if I do it with prod, then the resource group will also be the same, and that's not how we want it,
one way we can solve that is that we can use something called Terraform workspace variable,
it is that we can enter something that is to be processed or run in this file, which can be a
local, so we want to create locals that will do something, and that can for example be that we want to have
a base name, maybe a prefix or a suffix or something like that, so if I for example now write
workspaces suffix, so I want now that there will be an ending to the environment I am creating, which
will be a certain input, my suggestion from copilot here is that I can write in dev,
but then I again have hard coded it, I now wish that Terraform should take the starting point in how
workspace it is I am standing in, so the way I do that is that I can write Terraform workspaces,
and what it will suggest then, that is, the check, if the workspace is default, then it does not take anything,
if it is not, then it takes the starting point in Terraform workspace content, this will then represent
the names that I have in the list, that is dev, prod and stage, so if I then for example
wish that the names in my resource group should be local.sa name, or yes no, I meant not sa name, but rg
name, then we can now see here something that if we then write name, like, then we can check
what we want this resource group name to be, and we have already declared a variable that
will give input, because we are going to give the name to this resource group, so what we can then do then,
as we are familiar with earlier, then we take that we use var, resource group name, so variable, what we
want to give the resource group name, so that would be, for example, rg demo 001, and then we
add a dash, and local workspace suffix, so what I'm going to do, is that I'm going to
create, or I'm creating now, a local, no, sorry, it will be like that, so then we get local's
rg name as the name of that variable, and then I can change the resource group name here to local's
rg name, so then we get input from our variable, since we have declared that the variable resource
group name will come in, resource group name will come in, and then we have a local that processes that name,
and adds based on what kind of workspace we are in, so if I now run, I can now run an output,
let's see, like that, output resource group name, value, azurerm resource group rg name, which is then
this one, and then I will see the name when I run it, so then I can see something, that now I get
different names on this folder, and that can be done on several resources, I could, for example,
if I were to create a storage account now, then I could add on that there will be a
base name, or a suffix behind it, that it should be a random number, because we have always learned that
you can add on random numbers and stuff like that, but now I see that it says workspace dev,
so if I now take a terraform, plan, out, main, tfplan, I could have tried to add on that out,
it would be a main dev tfplan or something like that, but it really doesn't matter much,
and here we go, now let's see, it doesn't want to have the name behind it, wait a bit, of course,
forgot to save it, so, and then we run it again, and then we will now see that this
composition will then make it get a different resource group name, as you can see here, output,
resource group name, rgdemo01dev, so if I run now terraform, apply, main, tfplan,
you can see quickly what happens, now the resource group rgdemo01dev has been created, you can quickly
verify it in the portal, that we then take here, give it two seconds, there, rgdemo01dev, and that's
how we want it, and now we not changed anythihng here in the code, we have just changed how the
workspace we are in, and that's an elegant way to do it, if we think, okay, we're going to use the
repository, but we're going to make sure that when we're in a workspace, it's going to be maybe another one,
and it could be, for example, that if you store workspace dev, then you may not need a georedundant,
you can set that variables to be dependent on which workspace you are in, you can have, for example,
your own tfvars for each workspace, which makes you, if you are in dev, then you have a dev,
terraform.tfvars, if you are in prod, then you have a little bit of different content that can be there,
but you can also make it based on the same, but adapted, so we can check it, if I write
now terraform works select prod, and then I run the same command here, plan out main tf plan,
then we look here, then for the resource group prod, and that's how we want it, so we can run
show by, and then we will apply the deployment of this resource, which will then be a resource group prod
these are just examples to make it as simple and minimal as possible, of course, there are a lot of
resources you can deploy here, and now we just show via vscode against azure, in addition, we can
now set up, or we will see later how we use triggers or github actions, which is what triggers
or triggers which environment you are in, and that you may then have to go through some tests,
so you have to test, for example, if you have a very simple test, which is a manual test,
if I have now run the rgdemo001 dev, simple test, go to the graphical limit,
see the resource group, and it appears, great, then I know that it works, go right back,
run the prod, and then I get the prod resource group, then I have a manual test to check that this
has come up to run, of course, this is a manual, we do not want to do manual things, we want
that this should be a test that can go, for example, if we are going to deploy a website,
answer it this and this port, give it a feedback, it can be a network configuration, answer it to
that traffic comes through, there is a lot of different things we can set up, so be part of this
infrastructure deployment, which means that we can only use the same code base, but we change
which workspace we are in, and then we can see that we get different instances of the infrastructure
in the Azure portal, so now I have done that, now I have just known what workspaces are, and then we can
then easily now take and run, and that is important to think about, it is quite one of, let's say,
the advantages of the exercise here, one of the disadvantages of using workspaces is that you have to be
clear all the time on which workspace you are actually standing in, suddenly you think you are standing in
dev, and then you are standing in prod, and then you start doing things like that, then it can be a little
scary, but if I now write, for example, terraform destroy here, now I am standing in,
in the prod environment, then I would of course get a message that I am sure I want to do this,
I would then get, I could also show that I have used terraform plan destroy with a flag,
which plan that should be deleted, but if we now take yes here, then we clean up
this as well, because this is just to show how workspaces work, and then of course you have to
switch to dev workspace now, to delete that workspace, prod is deleted, dev, we take and destroy,
and that's fine, or you have to be aware that what is default workspace, it will also be there if
you have created resources under default workspace, which I had done with, in my case,
under the backend, so it does not belong to any workspace, some of it is on default
workspace, we can of course also use different terraform workspace commands, so we can,
we have used new, and then we have list, we have select, and we also have the option to of course
delete them, and similar operations, so I can now double check what the status is in the portal,
now both resource groups are gone, both dev and prod are gone, and this was actually just a simple
way of using workspaces, how we can add on suffix, which makes it easier that the same code base
is valid, because we could have had a lot of resources now with random, and for each workspace they have
got their own random string, so if we have had storage accounts, which I have used random on,
or other resources that I have been random on, then they will be valid within their workspace,
and those that are updated there, so that was really a simple way of using workspaces.